I think like hacking small businesses is
super fun like it's the every high
schooler's Dream is like hack their high
school and like change
their that's so true but like I totally
didn't do that when I was in high school
yeah to not endorse the behavior good
quality stuff but like the reason I
think people want to hack their High
School is because like you can be the
person like sitting in the classroom and
maybe the alarm Bell goes off and you're
you're kind of like sitting there smug
like I did that and nobody knows
[Music]
[Applause]
hey everyone we've all heard of project
Discovery right the authors of nuclei
htpx and countless other essential
security tools what you may not have
heard of however is their conference
hardly strictly security conference this
conference is happening April 25th from
8:00 a.m. onward virtually and it's
featuring the topic of everything open
source security tooling they'll have
speakers from top companies like versel
dated dog hash Corp and fastly and it's
oriented towards anybody who cares about
open source security tooling whether
you're a Bug Hunter a red teamer
security leader whoever uh there should
be great content for you at this
conference so if you're interested head
over to nu.
g/h ss24
hs24 right hardly strictly security and
then 2024 uh to sign up and register and
get in on that conference goodness all
right with that back to the
show all righty Mr Sam Curry we have
been prepping and we have so many
stories in the in the queue here welcome
to the podcast man hello hello yeah
thank you for having me man this is
exciting um Sam you you are just kind of
like a legendary bug Bounty Storyteller
so I'm I'm anticip this podcast being
largely me saying all right Sam tell us
about the time you got arrested at the
airport or tell us about the time you
broke every car in existence um and then
and then sort of hearing those stories
and then picking apart some technical
details I think that's how we're going
to go today but let's uh let's start
with a story that is not super technical
tell tell us about the time you got you
got detained at the
airport yeah sure so I was just
finishing up a trip from like uh us to
Japan I was flying back from Japan into
like Washington dillas airport so I was
like get to the airport like I'm
exhausted 15 hour flight I'm going
through the line like normal checkin you
know immigrations process but at the
very end of the line they like pull me
aside for secondary they're like hey you
know we just need to talk to you ask a
couple questions and I haven't traveled
like too much internationally at that
point so I was like you know it's a
normal thing whatever we'll go and I
realized I'm like the only person in the
secondary inspection and the cop who
walks me over there is like super nice
the process is just super very easy and
they're being super nice to me we
unloading all my luggage and going
through everything they're asking about
my trip I'm explaining everything about
my trip and then finally they ask me for
my device they say like hey can we just
see your phone and can you unlock it and
you know it's part of a normal
immigration process they asked for that
I didn't really think anything of it so
I gave the agent my unlocked phone and
then afterwards say I did that they're
like okay cool now just come over into
this room there's some people who want
to talk to you and at that point like
kind of alarm Bells yeah and it turns
out that there was a IRS C which is like
their criminal investigation and a
Department of Homeland Security Officer
in the room and they're both sitting
across from me and they said like hey
you know Sam you work here here's this
and I kind of was like they they had
like knew that you were flying back into
the country and they're like all right
we're gonna snag them at the
border yeah it was really interesting
because everything was planned and like
coordinated before twoo like they had
gone when we arrived in Japan everybody
in our group had like these little bag
notices and i' never seen them before
I've seen like the normal TSA inspection
things but these were like different
notices and I was like oh I guess they
changed the thing but when I went back
and they pulled me into that room what I
realized is that I was under suspicion
for like wire fraud and I was being
summoned to a grand jury in New York
yeah so I immediately asked him I said
like hey like can I have my device back
because I didn't realize this was like a
you know targeted thing and they say
like no we're actually allowed to keep
that because it's a like normal
immigrations process so at that point
like to sit there
heck it's super tricky too because even
if you're like the most clear conscious
person in the world or clear conscience
sorry your friend could have said
something that's like you know
incriminating what they'll do is like
parallel investigations so like even
though it was just me Under Suspicion
and it was like a weird narrative um and
I felt fine about it it's still like a
tricky thing where it's like something
on your phone is incriminating what did
you do what why why why were they
pulling you over at the
border yeah so what turned out happening
um immediately after that they let me
you have my device back and stuff and
they let me through I contacted my work
my work lawyers got involved um the
company I worked for is like a ulabs
which is like a cryptocurrency company
and what ended up happening is through
my security work at ulabs where we were
investigating like a fishing
website I had found a scammer's private
key leaked in the Javascript file and
I'd taken that scammer private key and
i' plugged into my metamask to see like
are there any recoverable funds and by
doing that they thought that I was the
oh no yeah it was really tricky too
because it allowed them to do a full
subpoena of my network so for instance
they had you know my ISP logs like in
AER thing oh my gosh yeah they read my
name like or they read my mom's name
because my internet was like stilling
her name so the whole thing was like
very yeah you you feel like you're you
know you've like killed some or
something but it really like shows you
how the sausage is made too because now
you you like you have some insight into
what lengths it can go to and what
information they can get about you just
like without you even knowing right like
you the first that you're hearing of it
they're sitting down with like a stack
paper like hey here's everything you've
been doing for the last few months and
you're like oh
cool what have I been doing for the last
couple months yeah well exactly yeah
it's very it it feels it's one of those
things you read about like always had
the stance that like I'll never be
important enough for them to like look
at my thing but then you realize it
could happen to anybody W that's crazy
and just to think that like how much of
the coordinated effort had to happen too
because they're like you know they were
definitely contact or contacting TSA and
saying like okay here's this guy's
picture he's coming in on this flight
like we need you to snag him and we need
you to get his phone and then like shove
him in this room and it's like oh my
gosh and like people are are going there
and it's like oh man
yeah I do wonder if it was because it
was International and like they had your
passport number what like they knew it
was you not just some other like Sam
Curry and like that's why they knew for
sure like okay let's let's take a look
on the way in and on the way out yeah oh
yeah 100% so I
guess this this is a good transition
into a different topic which is a topic
that you and I have debated many many
times uh it which is Sam you do
some you know for those of you that are
listening on the actual audio medium of
this podcast I'm shaking my hand in like
kind of like a iffy sort of way you do
some some borderline things you know um
and you don't really do it for the
bounties um and this is BG Bounty
podcast so we normally talk about bug
Bounty but I'm kind of wondering what
your motivation is behind all this and
why you're doing
that yeah sure and for for those of you
are listening who Justin just made it
seem like I'm you know killed somebody
or something no uh to clarify a little
bit the uh the hacking the sort of I
think what Justin's talking about is
like uh a lot of the hacking I do is
like not necessarily in Bounty programs
and it's not necessarily scoped in like
a specific like targeted way where it's
like you know they're inviting you to
come look at their stuff right I like a
lot of the hacking I do and when I
originally got into like web security
and hacking it was a lot of like really
like fun kind of curiosity right um so a
lot of the research we've been doing
like recently um to to to kind of give
context that topic when I started bug
Bounty like eight years ago right I was
like fresh out of high school and I
really wanted to make as much money as I
could right you know I grew up like
super like I'm really hungry for for
money right so I'm like hell yeah like
$500 Bounty there $1,000 Bounty there
and it's just like feeding like it's
going perfect right and I did that for a
while and I got a job in security and
I'm like you know the amounts keep
getting higher and like it doesn't like
hit the same way and then eventually I
kind of realized like you know like I
was I'm not a really huge spender I'm
very comfortable like I think in terms
of
like my I I think
like I guess I'm trying to find a way
describe it but but I think what I'm I
know that this is more you know this is
Strays a little bit more into life
philosophy as well because it's like
sure you know it's about this interest
that you have now and less about this
financi motivation that you had in the
beginning
right exactly yeah not to to kind of
wrap it down a little bit the the
hacking we do that we've done recently
is like you have a smaller group of
people that have been working with like
shabam sha like Ian Carol and I think
like as a group we kind of have like
this love for life for like hacking
stuff like it's it's this deep like
childlike curiosity of like seeing
something and like again like the
example of like a Subway card they like
I don't want to pay for the subway can I
get a million dollar Subway card to like
go
you know things like that and like we do
it in good faith and that's when people
say like I'm you know doing a gray line
or gray area where maybe they're not
explicitly abiding us to hack them but
you know I report them through a
security program or security team the
reason I've been able to do that so
successfully for like so long where it's
like I'm not getting in trouble and I'm
like helping these organizations is
because I think I have like very very
good intent like never once have I
wanted to exploit something like
maliciously it's always been kind of
like found it it's hilarious we had a
really good time it's a good story story
but it's fixed now and that's good right
so to talk about like that hacking like
I've kind of Fallen that's that's how
originally got in security and that's
kind of how I like keep my flame lit
right is like that sort of Interest
based hacking rather than like you know
money oriented or or even you know and
and I guess some of this has to do with
you know these are good stories as well
and and it's it's fun story to tell and
to share that that light that uh that
invigoration that passion for hacking
with others um and and so the I guess
the reason you're doing this is just
because of that that curiosity is that
accurate yeah I think absolutely I mean
like nowadays it's kind of like a it
Blends a little bit more into the normal
job space where security is like a
normal job that people do and like it's
a normal easy thing that you can kind of
get into as a career but like before
even like you know seven or eight years
ago it was a lot blurrier where like
hackers like the whole thing like every
hacker I knew was very like culture
oriented where they have like this love
for hacking love for security they have
this ecosystem and it's like this you
know like the the introduction song to
this podcast like Whitey cracker like as
a kid like I grew up listening to White
I'm 13 years old 14 years old and I'm
like you know he's like deep in the
matrix it's crazy like that world is
just like exciting right and I like as I
grew up that's like my I still have that
world right like it's 3 in the morning
I'm like deep in something like there's
like that really really deep passion
where it's like you want to do it
because you love it right that's that's
cool I have to say you know a lot of a
lot of people in this industry are green
hats you know to reference back to YT um
and and looking for the money in it and
and I mean I'll I'll say you know I do
bug Bounty full-time and I'm not
financially independent yet so uh I
definitely that is definitely a
motivation for me but it's definitely
cool to see someone a little bit more
motivated by the passion for the the and
and letting that be the leading Factor
right like I I think for me it's more of
like I look at a Target that I that I
that has good bounties on it and then
you know my passion for hacking comes
out against that Target because I I love
the day-to-day and I love getting in the
weeds with it and I love reading the
JavaScript files and figuring out how
stuff's working but it's still pointed
at the top level by that um you know
Financial incentive um and then also for
me buy the Safe Harbor incentive as well
which doesn't seem to be as big of a
thing for you like and we've we've
debated this you know um to the end of
the that we can debate this in our
little group chats or whatever but um
talk to me a little bit about why you
feel why you feel safe hacking all of
these targets and and yeah let's start
there yeah
sure I think it's maybe the safety is
kind of a I I think there's a lack
there's a small lack of safety where as
I get older and I think I'm mature and I
kind of settle into like this lifestyle
of like less risk that I'm kind of like
slowly like conis down but like for me I
see like hacking you know if there's a
company that doesn't have a security
program for instance we looked at
casinos recently I'll give you an
example where it was a really bad
interaction so we were investigating
like online gambling and online casinos
we found this one online casino and
there was a specific game in the casino
where you're able to replay the requests
and generate like an unlimited balance
and we were like this is hilarious we
didn't try to withdraw it or anything we
just reported it immediately we're like
hey guys like we found this how many
times did you do it Sam
and well I think I end up with a balance
I end up with a balance of $3 million in
my account right a little excessive
however what ended up happening that I
didn't realize is that the game
providers on the online casinos like
let's say you're a slot company and you
make the slot they're like a sub company
that sells the slot machine to the
gambling website okay and what end up
happening yeah yeah they the the
gambling website saw the slot machine
had generated $3 million and they just
cut them off completely they said we
don't want to do business with you
anymore because of this vulnerability so
I got on the phone with this guy in the
UK who runs the slot company and I'm
like hey I just want to report this
vulnerability and he said so you're the
guy who's committing fraud on on our
slot machine and I'm like so yeah at
that point it's like you know everything
in your head's like this wasn't my
intent blah blah blah but they could
still see you financially and it's like
a tricky situation that you have to
navigate right and of course the
complexities of like UK law versus us
and like whether or not you have
permission like it's very complicated
but like I think the leading thing is
like good intent but it can in this case
like stray because it does so you can't
leave there Sam what happened dude how
did you weasle your way out of this
one yeah so I whistled my way out by I
we had like a continued effort to like
report we reported the bug we worked
them the fix I communicated with the
casino I said hey I'm a researcher who
found this we've talked to the company
and we kind of messed it together and
things were like good and I'm sure you
can I'm sure you can convey to that
company as well like hey you know the
companies that are having their their
products assessed are the ones you want
to work with not the ones that you don't
want to work with right because the ones
that don't have the product assessed the
bugs are just sitting there waiting for
you know a malicious hacker to hack
them yeah exactly right like would you
rather have like one example where
someone you know it's $3 million but
it's never exploited or like thousands
of users that are just adding in $100
$200 and then slowly withdrawing money
it's a really interesting conversation
um I did a training one time I was I
worked for a consultancy and during the
training at the end of the training we
my people who are was working with the
web application security training we did
he said let's just like go to this uh
website here to kind of assess the you
know like look at the security of it and
it wasn't like a full like test where he
was like sending malicious traffic but
so when the audience was like Hey you
aren't really allowed to test uh random
websites right and then he responds well
it's like it's like it's a personal risk
thing where it's like if you're not
doing enough damage or not causing
enough noise like are you going to get
sued probably not but it's kind of like
your risk profile right yeah I mean is
there especially for you now established
at you know very publicly as a you know
white hat ethical security
researcher I bet that risk is probably
minimized even more for you than
somebody who doesn't have a track record
of ethical security research because of
the caveats in the you know Computer
Fraud and Abuse Act specifically for
good faith security
research yeah it it REM reminds me of a
skit actually there's a TV show called
Nathan for you and in the show he says
uh he's like hey I want to do this like
big public thing great it's a great show
it's fantastic um he says like hey I
want to do this thing which is like
totally a joke I want to make this
parody restaurant
and then he talks to the lawyer and he's
like to make this parody restaurant what
do I have to do and the lawyer says you
need to establish yourself as like a
comedian or a guy who does like pranks
so he quickly goes and does like a
performance art thing and tries to build
a name for himself right but I think
it's a security researcher like you can
Google Sam Curry and it comes up with
like the past work it's a legitimate
person right versus a lot of people I
see who try to reach out over email
they'll use their Alias and it's like
hacker 447 and they're like I'm not
going to give you my real name but
here's it's like I get it you know being
anonymous whatever it's great but like
you do come off a little more malicious
like that absolutely yeah I think
there's definitely something to be said
for that established track
record yeah so so when you're picking
targets um I know like a lot of it is
sort of just like the interest the like
the love for hacking um do you ever sort
of like choose not to hack things or to
go after certain things like I think
there's lots of different levels that
you can hack stuff at right so like you
can go like to the smallest level where
it's like an individual like us a
specific incen of a product or you can
like go to like the product itself or
like the parent company who owns that
product or like you know you can sort of
Step Up The Chain to like larger and
larger Scopes um where do you like to
draw that line because I know a lot of
people like we have mutual friends who
really love hacking small local
businesses and it's just like they feel
you know they get a really large amount
of impact out of that they feel you know
like that they're creating a lot of good
their Community like they have these
really great relationships with those
small businesses and stuff um but I
would say you probably aren't hacking
mostly small businesses you're you're
hacking mostly large businesses so what
where what sort of draws you in that
direction versus like the small business
route yeah so I think like picking
targets is really fun because like
mostly what I what I've been looking for
recently is like choke points where it's
like for instance like a single point of
failure that has like this cascading
effect where it's just like millions of
people right I think like hacking small
businesses is super fun like it's the
every high schooler's Dream is like heck
their high school and like change their
grades
whatever
that's so true but like I totally didn't
do that when I was in high school you
know to not endorse the behavior good
quality stuff but like the reason I
think people want to hack their High
School is because like you can be the
person like sitting in the classroom and
maybe the alarm Bell goes off and you're
you're kind of like sitting there smug
like I did that nobody knows right so
there's like this there's this like kind
of you can kind of do that with like
small businesses or bigger things like I
tend to focus on like big points of
failure like interesting things to me so
for instance the research we did with
like uh Nico specters with like car
security stuff where it's like something
I didn't know up until like a few months
ago is that you can scan a license plate
and it'll give you the vend number of
the car right and basically what that
means is for every car in the United
States you go
from how did you how did you H
how oh yeah so it's public you can pay
for an API that will basically do this
because the the yeah the DMV will sell
these records to these like small
companies or these like contractors that
provide them to like maybe you're a
traffic endorsement camera company or
something yeah so for about like you
know one and a half cents per API call
you can resolve someone's license plate
to the red number right so if you think
about it like if if I want to have fun
like acting stuff and it's like an
interesting thing and I'm not these
companies do have safe harbors a lot of
them it's like hilar ious to me like
being in line at Starbucks and like the
idea just the idea of it not actually
doing it but scanning someone's license
plate and making their car honk like
it's just hilarious because it's like
really fun and that's person in front of
you you know you see them pull pull up a
little bit before you on the way in you
know they're ahead of you they're
walking through the door you just take a
quick picture of their license plate and
when they get a line in front of you
make the alarm go off they leave line
and you just keep going
ahead Sam this is
it's a little yeah I mean like there's
there's
kind it really is like a something I
describe it right is like as an ethical
hacker you do have to kind of like put
away the idea of like you're never
actually GNA exploit it right and like
your intent is always good but like to
exchange that like I think you do kind
of have to like enjoy getting to that
point and like kind of dwell on that
just a tiny bit like um what I'm trying
to say is that like since you never
actually cross that line I think you
kind of have to extract as much fun as
possible from like dancing around it a
little bit if that makes sense well it
it it's very interesting too because the
attack things the attack scenarios that
the attack things the attack scenario
that you're going after is
really they're what if I were a
malicious hacker this is what I would
want to do you know I would want the
power to make somebody's alarm go off in
their car you know in my Starbucks line
and I would want the power to you know
unlock locks at
you know hotel or something like that
and and so all of these targets that
you're going after are very like
tangible black
hat stuff whereas you know like my
little sees surf or whatever that I
submitted to this to this company is not
something that most black hats are like
you know chomping at the bit to to
find yeah sure I there is that big
difference right where like I think
finding the SE sea surf can be just as
fun like page for it it's like still
it's still really valuable to the team
but like you know as like an individual
like let's say you're a homeowner and
you have a security system you kind of
want to have a clear conscious that like
nobody's like looking at you through
your camera right so maybe it's a fun
thing to do is like hack your home
security system right um there's a good
there's a guy named net spooky who's one
of the most talented great dude like
low-level engineer people fantastic like
genuinely great but I was having a
conversation one day and he told me
something that I didn't I never really
thought about it he's like he's like you
know you can like change your world like
if you see something in the world that
like you don't like or it's like you
have impact on the world and like you
can affect things like it's a really
lowle Point that's very cliche but like
very deep you know but he he's like you
know like if you don't like something in
the world you can change it so like the
idea of like you know I I'm curious
about the security of iPhones because I
don't want to get like my iPhone hacked
or whatever so it's like research iPhone
security and then maybe you find
something but clearly this isn't coming
from a place of privacy concerns for you
because you know you're pretty pretty
public
figure yeah I I think it's like
a a lot of it so like very like
straightforward uh there's like I kind
of dwell on I think that chaos and the
fun and like the kind of the pandemonium
of like creating like situations right
where it it obviously get kind of a rush
from like oh a journalist did a story
about a bug you found and like you know
there's people talking about like this
for instance uh recently there was a
vulnerability it was a huge effort by
Ian Carroll and Leonard wers and they're
most like talented Hardware people but
like they found this vulnerability where
you could unlock any hotel room right or
from a company called sath loock uh
whose parent company is dor M Caba but
to talk about that it's kind of funny
because it's like uh you know every
American's like nightmare for nighttime
television is like someone's getting in
my hotel room so it's hilarious to see
like oh CBS did a story about this bug
and like you know you're the who helped
with it that is that is really cool I
have to say that is pretty rad and and
and just jumping back to the the online
casino thing as well this has been a
pretty good entrance for you to do like
pen testing or security Consulting for
these companies as well
right yeah absolutely um it's it's a
really good like it's a sales it's a
salesperson's kind of like dream right
like if I wanted to sell a product to a
company say like a pentest or something
when you report a vulnerability you're
immediately providing value to this
company right so you say hey I found
this bug here here's what it is here's
how you can fix it and they say thanks
you know great to meet you you provided
value right so you have this good
relationship with this random company it
it's a really good like pipeline if you
did want to sell pentest right which is
like kind of an interesting thing
because it it there's a topic I've been
really like always curious about where
it's like
um inadvertently I think I end up in a
lot of situations where I'll report
vulnerability to aany and they'll offer
me money like not to disclose it right
and even though I never have it's very
sketchy because it's like I never asked
this company for money I never wanted to
like extract money from this company but
I plan on like blogging about it and
they're saying like hey you know maybe
you don't blog about this and maybe we
give you like five grand or something
and it's like to accept that feels it
yeah exactly like it feels like so so
like I think there's a lot of situations
that I think it's a really interesting
topic of like
you know maybe you claim you're like a
goodfaith researcher but you're hacking
all these companies and then you like
publicly humiliate the companies and it
builds up your reputation um yeah I
think that's like it yeah it's a tricky
kind of world no it it is for sure and
and there's definitely a lot of positive
attributes to public
disclosure um but it does it does I mean
I could understand the company's
position as well in that scenario of
like yeah we really don't want this
coming out under our name
um but it also makes that that sort
of it helps shift the culture a little
bit more towards something that that
makes security look like a good thing
rather than a bad thing which I think is
good you know so if at the end of the
day a company comes out and says hey we
were hacked by an ethical hacker here's
how we dealt with it here's the
disclosure process that sort of thing at
the end of the day if they have a good
PR team that should be spun positively
you know we we were able to secure our
devices you know in this specific scario
or something like that and I think what
most people just don't understand about
that is that every company has security
vulnerabilities so the fact that
somebody's fixing a security
vulnerability doesn't mean that it's bad
that they had a security vulnerability
in the first place it means that there's
one less of them you know so I I guess
I'm sure you have to do some coaching
with these companies too on how exactly
to portray that to the to the
public yeah it's it's super funny
because like I think a good parallel
there is like the power of marketing to
make a company look so and so secure
like the the Mythos of like apple you
know you now have this great big company
of Apple but like then you have this
security researcher who's able to like
hack apple and it like instead of you
know hey maybe apple has a company is
like any other company and has security
vulnerabilities the media story then
becomes like oh this hacker is just so
smart that they've hacked Apple but it's
like well no like it's just any other
company right like if that makes sense
basically what I'm trying to say is like
it does you know like the yeah
so do you find that a lot of companies
[Music]
are like is is there any correlation
between like size or revenue or anything
with like how good their security is or
is it pretty much because I notic like
when you're picking targets you really
don't like it never even seems to cross
your mind like oh this might be
difficult to hack you're kind of just
like I want to do this thing on the like
I want to the horn right whatever it is
and then you're just like fixated on
that and figuring out how to get there
it doesn't really matter like what the
company is or what their structure is
it's really just like one step towards
the goal um does it ever like get in
your head like oh man this company is
like so secure I don't think I'm going
to be able to hack it or like anything
like that yeah sometimes uh to give an
example there's like a funny enough I
was going through like the San Francisco
Airport and there was a coffee machine
that had like a robot arm and it was
like a scan on your phone to order a
coffee and the robot will make it for
you and I was like that's hilarious
right and it turns out that they deploy
this machine inside like Tesla so Tesla
has one inside their office and it's
remotely connected the internet you can
push commands to it through some website
right and I tried super hard to hack
this like coffee robot and it couldn't
find a single vulnerability but then
like as we're going along the airport I
see like you know Delta or like an
airline and no sooner did I find like a
critical vulnerability and like an
actual Airline than like a coffee
company right and it's like how do you
tell like what's secure what's not it's
really impossible right yeah I I I i'
I've thought a little bit about that I
was about to ask the same question Joel
and and and it's like one of the things
that I do like about bug bounty in
particular though is that you do get
some of the more hardened absc targets
right um most of the the the very
hardened absc targets are going to have
a bug boundy program because otherwise
how are you how are you you know getting
this hardened I'd imagine um and so
where does that where does the actual
technical challenge come in for you
versus like these goals that you set up
for like what you want to
accomplish yes so I think that the tech
challenge comes in when like the
technical challenge for me and like
where I really delve into the world of
like the technical challenge is like if
I have a goal and I can't quite seem to
get to the goal and I have to accomplish
some hurdle to get there um sometimes
it's like I'll discover some new attack
method or I'll find like some
interesting research because I want some
you know end goal um but other times
it's like very simple where there's like
no research involved everything is very
simple so for instance right like one of
the car vulnerabilities we found was
like a company called spirion and
there's millions of connected devices
that are behind this admin panel and to
get access to every single one of the
devices it was literally just SQL
injection like admin quote space pound
dash dash whatever and then you're end
yeah and it's like you feel like one
thing that's kind of frustrating for me
is like uh I've done like we we've we've
done like a lot of really cool blog
posts right where it's cool research
it's interesting and then like maybe I
wanted to like blog about like carcity
or something but like to actually get
there like the actual method is like
very simple and you kind of feel like
you're cheating people a little bit
you're like here's how we did this big
thing it's very simple and you're like
well yeah yeah and like you do wish it's
I I know exactly what you mean because
you do wish it's like more of a
challenge like some of these things are
like oh this is going to be so hard like
I'm going to have to go through all
these layers of security and all these
things and it's literally just like one
unauthenticated end point you're like oh
that was really I mean like yeah that's
bad but like that's so lame like I wish
it was more more fun than that to have
to get to here exactly yeah there's like
no story to it it just feels kind of
like you're cheaping it out a little bit
but yeah that's kind of thriving in that
technicality bit but that's the scary
bit though too is like you have these
goals very realistic goals very black
Hatty goals right the that you would
like that any blackout would like to
have and then they're like textbook SQL
inje and it's like oh
no so you know on one hand it makes for
less of a technically interesting story
for us that are you know often in the
weeds and hacking stuff that's really
hardened and go in there and figure out
okay you know it's just like a textbook
SQL injection but um from the story
perspective it actually even makes it a
little scarier because it's like oh this
was a textbook esql injection somebody
you know two months into their hacking
Journey could have found this and it it
does make you understand like because we
we know the vast amount of people that
have there's a very big difference
between the really really pro security
researchers and the amount of people
that get far enough to do a textbook SQL
injection right like there there's a way
bigger group of people that can do that
so there's by extension there's a way
bigger group of people that could do
this from a black app perspective um so
it's definitely it's definitely a little
bit a little bit scary to see that sort
of thing um I I I want to take uh take a
turn here and and talk about this don't
force yourself to become a Bug bney
Hunter blog that you put out I don't
even know this is probably like what 5
years ago maybe um uh but this is a very
interesting blog yeah four years ago
very interesting blog because
essentially this is something that you
and I kind of discuss on a regular basis
uh just because our personality types
are very different and how we approach
things and um essentially what you what
you talked about in this blog was this
whole concept of like trying to Foster
the passion for bug Bounty um versus
forcing yourself to be able to do bug
Bounty um and I think you can kind of
see this come through in your in your
hacking as well because you're you're
spending your time focusing and hacking
on things that you're passionate about
and when you became less passionate
about making
money uh you know your your Focus Shift
from bug bounty to this this more I
don't know mercenary hacking or whatever
you want to call this thing right um and
so I like what what what advice do you
have for people that are getting into
bug Bounty and are uh putting themselves
through the challenge of listening to
this uh podcast
um in in fostering that passion and
using that as a motivator for their bug
boundy
experience yeah so to talk about that
blog a little bit and kind of just like
the advice is like when I wrote that
blog it was at a time where like a lot
of people were reaching out to me like
hey I really want to get in security can
you give me tips can you Mentor me can
you give me these examples like how do I
get started what do I read what do I do
and like you have like kind of this
textbook person who they're sitting at
their desk it's 5:00 they got home from
work or school or whatever and they're
really stressed out because they want to
you know they see these people like
finding bugs and like how do I get there
and they're trying to read through and
like f through these books and maybe
it's not working super well where they
feel like you've you're kind of in this
mindset where you feel like you've got
this end goal and you have to like
really grind to get there maybe some
like there's something in your ethos
where it's like I need to be like
military about my study and like my work
routine and like commit to get there but
when I write about like hey it's like
don't force yourself to be a bug Bounty
Hunter it's kind of
a a preach to people I think like with
the same mentality as me there are
people um for instance Peter Pete yorski
who I worked at chopi I don't know if
he's still there but when he got into
bug Bounty he was someone who I think
was able to do it really really like
military kind of style where he got
himself started really quickly did
courses did trainings and it worked
super well like Pete became one of the
smart smartest people like in bug Bounty
and like in security that I knew and he
did it through like this kind of
military training where it was just like
a lot of like intensity um but me on the
other hand it was never like that right
so when people came to me and were like
how do I like grind like you grinded you
know like you have this work ethic it's
like well no I don't like what what I
did to get like bug Bounty is like I
kind of just like instead of like trying
to pick the books to read you know I was
playing video games and I like wanted to
get rich in the video game and like that
you know like fostering that like flame
for me was like so much better right
um and it depends like per personality
um I'm not no I'm not comparing anybody
in bug Bounty whatsoever to like Magnus
Carlson but there's a really funny thing
in the chess documentary about like mag
the world's greatest chess player like
total Genius Like fantastic guy but when
he got into chess like his parents
realized he loved chess and they
immediately got in this coach and the
coach guy the first one was like you
need to read these books and do this and
it didn't work out like he immediately
became you know but the second coach he
got he looks at Max Carlson he's like
let's just step away from it and like
let him play chess and like have a good
time with it so like he's reading like
you know like Donald Duck novels and
playing chess at the same time and it's
like he he becomes like the greatest
like chess player of all time right
where someone else like um there are
other there are other chess players uh
who are like world champions here who
have like different regiments right
maybe they were born into you know very
routine oriented like normal stuff um
but I guess what I was trying to get
from the blog post is basically like if
you feel like it's not working well and
you feel like there's all this
pressure I've never once found the bug
like in that pressure I've always like
when I find good bugs it's like relaxed
and good yeah so maybe don't force
yourself yeah no that's that's that's
yeah I'm sorry go ahead
Joel yeah well I was just going to say
like I've definitely felt a lot of this
as I progressed throughout my career
both through bug Bounty and like
professionally especially with like the
lack as I've had both there's a lack of
financial dependence for me for bug
Bounty and that's also changed my
mindset on it significantly where when I
was first starting bug Bounty I was like
you know a lot of other people who are
just starting bug bunny they don't have
a lot of money it's like a really good
way to earn money and like put your
skills to use and it's like engaging but
then it shifts just like any other job
where it becomes work and it becomes
like a thing that you feel like you
start to have to do and like especially
when they take it full-time like you
know I'm sure there are some days you
wake up and you don't want to hack
Justin but you have to right like you
need to submit a bug to get you know
some money today um or in three weeks or
whatever but you know and so I think one
of the things I really like about how
you hack Sam is that like
you it's not like it's almost never
about the money right like it's about
like oh this seems really interesting
like I want to just like follow this and
this is so so engaging and that's when I
find just like what you said like for me
that's how I feel engaged when I'm
hacking like it's not when I'm stressed
it's not when I'm like oh I need to hack
oh I need to hack I need to be doing I
like I feel like I have to hack no it's
I want to hack like oh that that's
really interesting I wonder how that
works uh oh that's like a super
interesting thing it's not about the
Bounty it's not oh do they have a bounty
program it's like oh that it'd be really
cool if I could do XYZ like I wonder if
that's possible um and I think like that
Natural Curiosity is so much better of a
driving Factor than like chasing after
money cuz the money will like facilitate
things in life but it's not going to
really necessarily make you happy and I
I would like to know sort of how you
balance that because I know you didn't
always have a full-time job and so
hacking a lot of time was a source of
money for you did you have to do like
sort of dual like hacking where you're
like hacking for money and then also
hacking for fun or like how how did you
manage that yeah sure so I can I can
actually share like my full kind of
progression right so like my first job I
worked at like a faster
um so it was very like at that time it's
like the end of high school I'm like
trying to balance like paying certain
bills or whatever and then I got into
bug Bounty where I'm earning like let's
say like an extra like $1,500 a month
and for me that was huge that was enough
to like quit my job I'm still my parents
this time and then after that uh I
started doing like bug money full-time
where I was maybe earning I think like
in a year or two I earned like 100,000
USD a year which is great for like pokon
and uh at that point I was like really
enthusiastic about it but I wanted more
stability because I felt kind of
stressed I was in college and I was like
still earning money from bug Bounty but
I was like this is really unstable what
if it all falls apart so then I got a
job at hacker one where I worked as a uh
security analyst or triager so when I
was in college I worked as uh doing
triage for hacker one and I had that
kind of consistent income but I wasn't
doing enough bug bounty on the side so I
was actually making I think less but it
was like stable air quotes you know um
and then I transitioned sorry this is
like the full recap maybe it'll help no
this is good because I think this is I
mean I took a very similar approach I
think a lot of people do especially when
they're going back and forth between
like full-time work and Bug buny work
and and all that so yeah this is awesome
yeah right yeah like the transition
part's really good but at after kind of
college I I did like a year of college
and I stepped away and at that point I
wanted to transition into more like a a
real security role so I worked at a
security consultancy where I was doing
40 hours of pen testing it was like pen
you pentest grind you know that was a
that was definitely a grind um it's
probably more than 40 hours but it's
very routine like hacking the same thing
but it's very it was good money and it
was a good salary and I didn't feel like
content at that point because I felt
like I was losing potential because you
know I there's like Tommy deos who's
making like you know it's like my ssrf
was like 50k I'm like geez like what is
going on like uh yeah and that was like
the Y the peak of the Yahoo program
right and at that time with the Yahoo
program like going off I was like I need
to step away from Consulting so I kind
of like put my two weeks I like hey I
really appreciate the opportunity but I
want to do full-time bug bunny so then I
transition to like maybe three or four
years of like full-time hard like bug
Bounty which was like your endome goes
up a lot and like it's you learn a lot
but it's really stressful and at the end
of that um at the end of that four or
five years was when cryptocurrency stuff
started to kind of take off and I
thought like can can I pause there so oh
yeah go ahead I'm wondering why that was
stressful and what kind of is it because
the income was inconsistent or because
for me one of one of the things that's
been really interesting with fulltime
Buck Bounty is you get a big you know
windfall essentially from you know a
great event or you know popping a Target
or whatever and then you know the next
month comes around and sometimes you you
still feel like oh I need to hack again
to pay my bills but my bills are paid
for the next year you know like so so
can you talk a little bit about what how
that was stressful for
you yeah sure I think
one big thing for me at the time is like
I think when I'm hacking or when I'm
involved in something I'm I'm either
like zero or 100 right and one thing is
for me that is like I didn't really
address until like later in my life is
I'm a type one diabetic right I take
like insulin every day for like meals
and stuff and I like neglected like
caring for myself pretty much up until I
was like 20 22 or something you know so
basically my blood sugar it was like
four times the normal level it was
supposed to be from when I was like 12
to like 20 right and that like took like
yeah it was really really bad there's
probably going to be some you know like
I have like Nerf damage and stuff and
things like that but like
uh when I was like doing full-time Buck
Bounty um there were other things too
that kind of came up
where every morning like it was kind of
funny I think the other day I was like I
was like am I allowed to call myself
like a bug Bounty person I realized that
like pretty much every day for the last
like seven years I've consistently just
like woken up immediately gone to my
computer the whole day is at my computer
doing security related stuff like every
single day and a lot of the people a lot
of people I know are the same right
but it didn't it doesn't really help go
towards a balanced lifestyle um the the
version of me in high school I wanted to
make a ton of money I wanted to like you
know do these really cool things and I
really committed to that one bit right
but now I have like a girlfriend
responsibilities like duties and I'm
doing full-time bug Bounty and I can't
like let that go where it's like very
stressful because like I'm committed to
like you know if I don't out earn myself
the month before I just kind of blow up
a little bit that's that's a really triy
piece right because it's like why do we
feel like [__] if we have a downtrending
month after we just had us you know you
know yeah go for
it it's it's because it's because your
your performance is directly based on
your your personal um you know like H
how how good did you do right did you
find the bug did you did you break
through the really hard wall and if you
don't then you see it as a personal
failure even though you're dealing in a
in a world where you can be hacking on
the coffee machine for three hours and
find nothing and you can hack on Delta
for 30 minutes and find a critical right
and and the world's just weird and
unfair like that totally agree yeah like
the the unfairness I totally agree with
it's like you know you're looking for
like ideally you know if you like lift
weight you you're slightly increase your
whatever over time it's a very
consistent good reward but like you know
like some people like chubs like one of
the best Packers ever has like a Blog
where he's like I wasn't able to find
bugs for months and it like burned me
out but it's like people have down
months like you say but like mentally
being able to separate that is like for
a lot of us it's really hard yeah yeah
so what was your mental during that time
those like four or five years when you
were doing bug Bounty full-time was it
cuz now again like now it seems very
much like goal oriented hacking back
then was it just money like just
focusing on paying bills and finances
and all that kind of stuff and just
doing hacking as a job more than
anything or like did you find any fun in
it yeah I think it was a mix of uh like
bills but also the community that time
that was when I was like most involved I
think in the bug bounding community that
was like live hacking event after live
hacking event everybody I know was doing
full-time bug Bounty and like my whole
world was like bug Bounty right like
everybody I kind of talked to bug Bounty
bug bounty B Bounty where now it's like
you know I have friends in security who
are doing consulting or like EDR or like
these things and there's all these
different worlds right but at that time
the only thing I cared about is like am
I gonna get MBH like I gotta go for
these Awards you know mean I definitely
feel that yeah got yeah it's a different
type of goal you know it definitely is
yeah and and there's a lot of aspects to
it because the and and I know for me
just sort of on the flip side going back
to the motivation conversation is like
for me my passion I I have a strong
passion for hacking obviously but um for
me I think the the dopamine payout or
whatever is is oriented a little bit
more towards success as a generic entity
rather than hacking in general you know
like like I love the process of hacking
um but my payoff comes from succeeding
in some way right so so that's why
that's why like for buck Bounty that's
why I can pick a Target and I can say
okay my goal is to you know hack this
target or whatever and and make this
money or whatever and it's not and goal
oriented hacking is really helpful we've
talked about that on the Pod it's it's
super invigorating when you actually pop
the goal of of what you want to do um
but I think for me it's more it's more
of a of a success oriented thing and
that's why I I have a little bit more I
think sustainability than most people in
Buck Bounty um because it's like okay uh
let me just set set these these
arbitrary little little goal posts right
okay I want to get this this extra
Gadget or and and we've talked about
this as well it's like you you gotta
recognize little pieces of success along
the way with hacking because sometimes
you are going to slam your head against
the wall and you're not going to get
anywhere but if you if you recognize oh
hey there's a there's a gadget that
allows me to um you know do a path
traversal in an oo flow even though I
don't know how to leak the code I can
lend it on any page in the domain right
um that Gadget alone should be a little
bit of a payoff for you uh you know from
a motivation perspective um and keeping
those up I think really that that's kind
of where where my motivation comes from
in these sort of scenarios um which
which is which is is is pretty different
and and the long time bug Bounty flow is
is is really tricky to stay healthy
throughout that whole thing and you
mentioned um I think in that blog post
that we were talking about that don't
force yourself to be a bug bounty hunter
that you have you know dealt with
burnout along the way um and I'm
wondering you know how how you deal with
that and how because four years as a
full-time Buck Bounty Hunter is a long
stint so how did how did you get over
those and how did you return to hacking
when you were kind of
burnt yeah and also maybe that maybe
that'll cycle back in because I know we
kind of paused you know your your story
as you were going through sort of how
you got to where you you were so um I'm
also curious how that played in oh yeah
absolutely I think like four years was a
long stent for like anything I think too
and like one big part of that is like
you're learning like the whole rest of
your life like you know like I'm talking
to people who are having kids you're
getting married there's like so much
like you're trying to so maybe like
you've got your I mean it's so much just
try to process right but to go to the
bug Bounty part where it's like burnout
can be really tough where I mean some of
seriously like
maybe I think a year and a half ago I
probably had like the worst year of my
life because I was removed from I I kind
of removed myself from bug bounding I'll
talk more about that and I didn't really
have any metric to kind of feel
successful or like anything to tie my
success to or happiness to and I just
felt very stagnant and the reason for
being was uh to to go all the way back
the the four years of bug Bounty it had
its highs and lows like its roller
coaster like everything else you know uh
one of the events like end up like
working with like doggy G we got like
first and second place was really I was
really happy with um and that's like a
really high moment for me is like being
able to get the awards like going out on
stage and it's like you've done a really
good job you feel great but then the
other months where it's like you don't
find anything it's you know but like
dealing with that is super tricky
um and it's like a life thing I think
where you're trying to learn how to deal
with that um but what ended up helping
me was transitioning to um starting a
consultancy which is what kind of I did
after that where instead of doing bug
bount I wanted to get kind of more
involved in the pentest world and uh I
kind of started the story a little bit
but at that time we were auditing a lot
of like cryptocurrency stuff because
there's always these crypto bug Bounty
programs and they we realized that they
didn't really have a lot of web security
so we started doing web web Consulting
for like you know these big exchanges
like bit FX or coinbase or like uh openc
things like that right and we me Brett
Beer House Mike Robert we had this small
team of people who built this company
out over a little bit over a year right
and it was really really fun where you
started this big process where you've
got your like statement of work these
documents everything signed up and
you're getting clients and stuff and you
have that growth right so it was a year
of building something great and like
you're really happy about it but what
end up happening was like we one of our
com our customers that we worked really
closely with they actually acquired the
company and we went over to work as
employees and at that point in time like
it was really great and we're doing a
lot of work but it slowly kind in the
less work and must work and uh I wasn't
really I was working at a private
company now and there wasn't a lot of
security people and the work we were
doing like wasn't I didn't really feel
like I was like maybe doing the same
level of work I was doing before and it
kind of turned into just not really
having any positive feedback right and
that year of my life I think was like
really not knowing how to like manage
that was really really hard um but yeah
yeah yeah I mean it sounds like you were
kind of in a bit of a flux where it's
like you know you had just come off this
sort of
high-intensity push for the last couple
years of just like non-stop grind and
then you suddenly fell into this very
stable
situation um but almost like too stable
where it's like there's no like where's
the excitement like there's nothing
really like it's
so day in day out just like come to work
leave work come to work leave work like
you know and there's it's just like not
very fulfilling um and is that sort of
the point where you started doing the
big Target hacking or like were you
already kind of doing a little bit of
that and you were like let's get back to
that yeah so I I think I was doing a
little bit of that but I kind of
transition to it a lot harder at the end
of it because uh it really does suck
because bug Bounty specifically too is
like you work you put in the hours you
get a bounty like it's a very the cycle
is there right but with a salary it's
just so disconnected of like do you do
extra work this month no work this month
it shifts a lot like realistically like
it's going to shift a lot right but you
still get that consistent paycheck every
month and then your brain kind of stops
it like removes that Association you had
before of like time effort money right
so like so true yeah it really sucks um
and at that point yeah I kind of was
like I want to do more of what I love
that has like results and stuff right
like uh working uh the shs I think too
kind of felt the same way and had a long
conversation with about it where he has
done like so much security work and like
provided like so much value and done bug
boundy so much but like he at the end of
the day he wanted to do like high impact
vulnerability research so we kind of
worked together on that and that changed
a lot right yeah so I I will say I
noticed that you do a lot of
collaboration and stuff um with other
hackers um oftentimes a lot of the same
hackers but what has sort of LED you to
like what I know a lot of this stuff you
like what you'll just like be in one of
our group chats and you it'll be like
four in the morning and you'll just post
I just found some crazy vulnerability
like XY and just like okay I'm G to go
to sleep now you're like oh okay that's
that's pretty wild um but that's not all
the time like I know sometimes you do
sort of fall off into your little
hacking cave and you just you're there
secluded doing your own thing but other
times there's like this secret sort of
huge force of hackers behind a lot of
the work that's being done um of really
really talented people working together
to to sort of exploit large systems at
scale
um I like to think of it sort of as
putting together like an A Team uh where
you're like you know all these action
movies are always like you got the
hacker and the and the T guy and the
driver and the the gun guy like and and
it's kind of like that when when you're
like building together as a team but you
have you know so many people we all know
so many people that are really really
good at these things how do you um you
know pull your team together how how are
you deciding you know who you want to
work on stuff um like when to reach out
for help and not just do something
yourself cuz it's not like there's a
bounty here it's not like you're at risk
of you know duping or anything like that
like you're very deep into these systems
most times to the point that nobody else
is so it's not really like there's a
pressure thing what sort of what's the
thought process when you start to reach
out and build like pull more people into
these projects a lot of times like the
initial thing for me is like a specific
question right so for instance uh like
Joel you're one of the greatest like
mobile hackers I we like I I know
nothing compared to you for instance so
like whenever like something mobile
related that's like confusing or it's
like really difficult to kind of
approach like I'll often just like reach
out to you and like hit you up and then
you know that point you're like in
corellia making a script and then like
it's this collaborative process where
now you're involved because you've done
the thing and you're invested you're
like okay what's going on and then maybe
you want to keep working on it I nagged
a lot like for the Apple research like
uh Brett one of the when I first started
it it was just me and I was doing it and
I was sending everything to Brett he
must have gotten like he's got kids he's
got a wife it's dinner time his phone's
probably blown up I'm like Z dude like
please like please hop on this like and
uh he eventually did right and then he's
like what's all the fuss about he joins
in he's like oh this is actually
interesting so I think like uh I don't
know I don't have like there's no
elitist like there there's like this
concept of like a hacker group or
whatever where like you used to have
like this hacker name and like this big
uh you know be like team poison or
something you've got like the eight
members and like this kind of elite
organization or something but for bug
Bounty stuff it's just like hey I'm
gonna spam you stuff and if you can help
if you want to and then maybe you like
add one thing and add another thing and
like we build the full picture and then
like people get credited and stuff right
um yeah so yeah that's good no that's
good I mean I think what I see
especially is everybody ha has these
skill sets it's just like you said like
I'm good at mobile so if somebody needs
to unpin an App instead of spending four
hours like trying to break their head
through their computer screen to like
figure out how that works they just send
me a message and I'm like in 30 minutes
I'm like okay here you go all done and
like that sort of Outsourcing of work
can be so useful when you're attacking
these big targets because the it's just
like lots of different skill sets right
I think that's one of the a one of the
really awesome things I've noticed as
you attack targets across all spectrums
of things whether it's Airlines whether
it's Hotel key cards whether it's isps
TL
Starbucks like whatever it is right like
they're all using different Technologies
they're all using different um you know
setups and configurations and the method
of attack can be different a lot of the
time but um you have a really good way
of identifying like hey you're good at
this thing like help me with this and
then not only that but you like pick up
that skill yourself really well and then
you're able to sort of like Foster it
and use it later um and and I I think
it's really amazing to just sort of see
the research as it goes um I did want
you to talk a little bit about hack
compute actually because as we're
talking about sort of these like big
hacking projects and stuff I know that
this is something that you and chubs and
a couple other people um have been
working on sort of maybe quietly is uh
behind the scenes um but uh yeah you can
you just tell a little bit about what
that is and everything yeah sure so ha
compute is kind of like this fun group
we put together where it's like we
wanted to have like this idea like old
school style Zen publication where it's
like fun hacking research that's maybe
not you know either bug Bounty that it
doesn't end in like oh and then we got
20,000 through it's mostly just kind of
fun research right and the idea for it
originally is that it would kind of
exist as like this kind of like nameless
each blog post would have a different
group of collaborators and each post is
just you know um and then we would do
cool like high impact research or things
that were interesting to the people who
wanted to contribute to it um and the
way it came about was because uh when we
did the car hacking research if years
ago um I like it it was kind of like me
and a few people originally who were
pushing towards like let's do car
hacking and had this big group chat and
there's a lot of people involved but the
blog actually got ended up getting
published on Sam curry. net my domain
and even though like the names were
listed collaborators I still like
there's this like kind of small tension
of like hey like we all this work but
it's hosted on sam.net and also like I
just feel super guilty about it because
it's like when people go to see the blog
post it's on sam.net like it you know
it's like the Facebook like a Mark
Zuckerberg production whatever for and I
just like it it doesn't feel good
because you feel like you're stealing
people's credit right and the idea for
ha compute is like this idea where it's
like intentionally collaborative where
it's behind a name um and that's kind of
like the origin of it
right yeah that's awesome that's awesome
that makes a lot of sense and and that
way you know it can be and that way lots
of different hackers can contribute it
too and it can sort of just be a hub for
really awesome hacking achievements um
definitely definitely excited to see
where that goes and and uh if I if I
ever pop anything not Bounty
related I'll let you know and we can see
if we can put it up there yeah we love
we love
that okay I did want to talk about some
technical stuff too hold on I'm sorry
before we get before because I I I do as
well but I actually wanted to hit one
more non-technical topic before we
transition is that fine okay okay so
last one and then we'll transition into
some some hacking stories and getting
the technical
content we have our our little dock over
here and it says one of the things you
wrote down here are we really even
solving problems here with with Bounty
and I think this is a really interesting
question and one that I kind of want to
flush out a little bit with you
like what are your thoughts on the
efficacy of bug Bounty with regards to
security as a whole uh yeah let's leave
it at that
yeah absolutely so the conversation
around like is bug Bounty solving the
issues like I think you could approach
it at every angle and pick the
supporting evidence and prove every
point so for instance I could say like
bug Bounty isn't solving any problems
because your CES surf isn't fixing any
real bug that a nation state and
someone's always going to social
engineer and blah blah blah and it's
like but on the other hand it's like bug
bounty has like created this like
culture of like absc Focus like web like
heavy like it's it's kind of brought
itself like there's these old school
hackers who are doing like internals and
windows and like they saw web security
as like this kind of lame like crossy
scripting it's like who cares but like
nowadays like everything is web like if
you wanted to pick a single category of
research to get into where you have the
most impact and most you know
expandability it's like web security
right and I think bug bounty has like by
everybody having bug Bounty programs
like pretty much every company has a bug
Bounty program now at least a security
contact right okay all right I with that
caveat I'll I'll let you off there's
still so many programs that don't pay
for for for bounties which which is
really crazy to me but yeah there
there's definitely been a big expansion
of like security. txt and that sort of
thing in the past couple
years yeah I'll even name drop like cod
FL like 5K Max like you run the internet
dude like you've got like 80% of every
website it's like please know like
increase your bounties because nobody's
like hacking on it for money
because that of a
Target exactly right like I totally
agree that like some companies like 100%
but like the difference between like you
know and it's such a I'm not that old
but even like five years ago or six
years ago is like you've got like Yahoo
and like the big companies like but like
companies like uh big big companies are
being brought and like doing like money
right so with the question of like are
we even solving stuff um I think that
like aback and like catching out these
like single issues is contributing to
this big kind of security culture
knowledge base that is like really
really affecting change and like
security stuff and you're seeing a lot
of pushes now from for instance like a
jack cable was a very prolific bug
Bounty Hunter and he got involved in
like cisa and like US Government stuff
and he's helping with this push towards
like secure code by Design right which
is a a huge really great effort of like
you know can we fix can we can we take
what we've made adjust it a little bit
and fix it like fundamentally and I
think that's like a really great push
but that's kind of my conversation about
that how I feel so go ahead go
ahead well I would say definitely like
from a program side and like a security
team side um you know I think most
companies should have some sort of at
least a security contact but maybe a bug
Bounty program as well like all the bug
Bounty program really does is like offer
people an incentive as well well right
like if you want people to come and hack
on your company and find vulnerabilities
externally then you can offer money for
that and you can put money where your
mouth is but if you just want a place
for people to be able to reach out you
can do that without a cost um I think
it's important that like you know no no
products is going to be free
vulnerabilities right and like
eventually there's going to be some
hacker who's going to want something
from like your company and they're going
to try and find some way to do that and
if you have some ethical way for them to
reach out that's fun f um but like it's
not an end allb solution it's not a
silver bullet it doesn't actually create
like Security in a sense it like it's
just part of the it's like what you said
it's like it all flows into like what is
security as a whole like what's your
security posture and like having some
way for external researchers ethical or
bug Bounty or whatever to reach out is
just part of that posture but it's not
like oh we have a bug b program now like
thankfully all the hackers are now going
to submit their vulner abilities to us
and we'll never like fire all those
absec Engineers we just need one guy to
triage like that's you know I think
that's a really common misconception
that a lot of companies think is like oh
once they spin up a bug Bounty program
now they're secured on all fronts and
it's like you all you've done is created
a doorway or like a mailbox for people
to like insert letters but people could
just like ignore that and just walk past
it and not give you the letter or like
post it on a blog or like Reach Out by
email or like all these other ways so I
think po it
you know it's a
good yeah maybe like ha
comp.com yeah but no I I totally agree
like I think um it's it's definitely
like just a little a little piece and it
does solve like some things for sure
like there are absolutely things that
get caught through bug Bounty that
wouldn't get caught otherwise but it's
such like a niche almost right it's not
pen testing it's not internal security
it's bug it's like its own little part
of the pie in order of operations there
too like like I feel like you should not
have a bug boundy program if you don't
have tofa enabled you know or if you
don't have like a hardware key or
something like that because at the end
of the day most of the most of the
attacks are occurring from fishing and
stuff like that but one of the thing and
I've been kind of toying around with
this in my head for the past couple
years of like okay you know if an
attacker is really going to go in
they're going to go in bya this pathway
right um but at the end of the day if
you have a bug
that is just going to let you let's just
say theoretically you had a zero day RC
on engine X right
like that you're always going to use
that like you're not going to go fish
somebody if you've got a a way in where
you have no interaction with any other
people especially when these hackers are
are spending so especially the highly
technical ones are spending a lot of
time with the computer you know and and
and less time you know deceiving people
and you know building those those skills
required to do that um so I definitely
think there's there's two sides of the
coin and I definitely think there is a
lot of risk with with um from an absec
perspective and I think the the the
biggest risk though that I think bug
bount really helps absolve is getting
users very very deep into your
application where actual you're getting
hackers really deep into your
application where the users are and then
getting train security eyes on that
incentivized train security eyes on that
right because you know all it takes is
one user that says oh you know in this
weird obscure functionality we up the
you know deep deep deep deep deep in the
application where the URL says oh you
know user ID equals 1 two3 what happens
if I change that to a four and then now
your database is gone right and so
getting deep into that and and getting
hackers that deep will help prevent
those very obvious you know
vulnerabilities as well as secure some
of those more AP type type threats wa I
mean are you with me on that I
mean right yeah 100% I mean like the the
idea of like an exploitable cve that
comes out and and like you have like
20,000 researchers who immedately spray
it on every organization like that has
it reduces the time defects I think
significantly yeah yeah yeah absolutely
I love that it how it highlights like
key areas that need fixing right like
systemic things like if you see
researchers like every time an xss comes
in like they're getting an atto because
your cookies are not properly secured or
your off token is stored in a bad place
like that's a really easy business
justification to be like hey hey we have
external security researchers who are
finding this problem we need to fix this
like ASAP right and like there there's
like a one toone correlation there but
it's not always that like it's like
sometimes it'll be like a broken social
media link and you're like how do I
bring this to my engineering team and be
like hey guys uh the Twitter link is
broken they're like what is what
security oh God yeah no that that that
is a
pain hey guys real quick I just wanted
to give a shout to the hacker content
team they have been absolutely killing
it the past couple months taking the
content from the podcast and condensing
it down into consumable social media
posts whether it be shorts or text posts
or whatever they've been rocking it so
uh I just wanted to give them a shout
out and let you know that they do all
sorts of cybercity content as well as
social media management they do
technical blogs they do uh comprehensive
social media management uh so if your
organization could benefit from any of
those types of services make sure you
head over to hacker content.com drop
them a line and mention the podcast when
you do to get your first month of cyber
security content marketing services for
free all right that's it let's get back
to the Pod all right so with that let's
uh let's let's set those those
um stories and and more philosophical
stuff aside and let's go deep into some
some technical stuff sound good all
right sure cool so Sam you have so much
research online so many stories um so
many cool things that uh we need to
unpack here but one of the things you
are most well known for is secondary
context bucks um I don't know did you
like my first exposure to secondary
context was you uh did you did you coin
that term same I did yes so bad
funny I appreciate yeah it's funny
seeing that term like used like oh my
God someone's actually using that word I
just put those two things together a
title that's clutch man but it I mean
obviously I'm sure some OG you know on
some log back in like you know 28 well
you know 2028 208 28 2008
yeah no um you know way back wrote
something about it but you know that
blog or that talk that you did on
secondary context stuff was my first
exposure to that um and and I think it
it really made it more uh widely
recognized in the industry um and we
have a cool cool bug we can talk about
that with the Starbucks bug um and
that's on s.net as well that you guys
can go read about but talk to me about
when you started realizing secondary
context bugs were a thing and how you
start of working through that whole
concept right yeah so my initial
exposure to like secondary context bugs
was on uh Yahoo's Luminate which was
like Yahoo's small business platform for
like deploying websites and stuff and
what I realized was that uh I originally
thought it was like path like file path
traversal right because I was like able
to reverse and like add directories and
I'd been spending so long in this one
app and I was just like getting and I
eventually started testing for it I'm
like oh my God there's file path Ral and
even in it's funny too because I blogged
about it and even in the blog post I
refer to it as like I remember this
local F remember so this was not a f
path
traversal it was not yeah it was
actually HB path traversal but even at
the time like I'm like I guess the S
password file just didn't exist and it's
like no that's just not that's not what
was happening um
so with that kind of exposure to it uh I
started looking for similar stuff in
more and more places and I eventually
realized that like the internet was
slowly being built towards this like
interesting like Network model where
like oh you want to serve a CDN from
like dubdub dub. yahoo.com where like
you want to serve images but you don't
have to like you've got this very
complicated configuration of like proxy
rules and different passes so maybe that
you know slash images instead of being
like a folder on like one box because of
like load Bal how crazy that be if it
was just all served from the same box
now the SL images route is being proxied
to like some internal server for a CDN
right that's interesting do you think is
a function of needing to do load
balancing more
effectively I think it's a mix of things
right I think that um if you're a team
who you have like you know maybe a
static blog but at the same time like
you have uh authentication functionality
on your static blog and the team who
deploys you know you've got like devops
team one devop scham 2 and then like you
to kind of merge them together sometimes
the easiest way to like differentiate
routes and folders and things I think is
by adding that reverse proxy and then
separating the services into two um so
yeah that's probably the biggest thing
that I've seen from like the engineering
side is it's the service like that
service aspect a lot of people don't
think about this because they're not in
in engineering org but for engineering
orgs like they split up functionality
into Services right and services are
separately deployed and in order for
these things to interact with each other
instead of having just one giant
application that's handling everything
from one place that can interact
internally with everything itself it has
to make some sort of call whether that's
like grpc or Kafka or whatever like and
a lot of times it's just hdp they build
in HTTP client like for that service
that just like calls internal endpoints
on that other service on you know their
internal Network and it passes data back
and forth and it's a lot you know it's a
lot more simple than people would think
where they're like oh like you know they
must have they're they're load balance
it's like no they there's two separate
services and they have to talk to each
other somehow and they just did that
with an HTP request and they did it
really really quickly and effectively in
a in an insecure way and that's where
things are starting to fall apart right
yeah exactly and like even uh external
Services too like apis like maybe you've
got like a Maps plugin like you want to
serve that data and you pass in a path
that goes like Google Maps API
and like it's very very interesting how
like complicated it goes I think one of
the reasons like this kind of research
kind of came about there's different
people who had worked on like similar
things in the past there's really
excellent blog post like France Rosen um
he he he should have been like he should
be the originator um his work with like
Matias and others like I think probably
even a few years before that talk and I
even messaged him when I gave a talk I
said like I feel like this is similar to
a lot of work that you've done in the
past and I was like if there's anything
here like I'm going to I'm making surey
to credit you for a lot of this
um I want to make sure I'm not like
stepping on your toes a little bit but
uh I wanted to say like
the the way
that the way that totally lost my train
I thought but maybe I can maybe I can
reect you that that's fine the the so as
you're starting to develop this this
understanding of essentially modern web
architecture where these reverse proxies
are are in place like that um and
the the tricky part for me still lies in
where does the authentication live
because there's there's a lot of there's
a lot of uh secondary context path
diversal all over the place but the
backend server is also using o and it's
just like okay well I can hit a
different endpoint you know and
sometimes you can do weird stuff with
that like like SE surfs or like um you
know some sort of um method confusion
and that sort of thing but
uh the majority of the time that have
understanding that off piece is really
is really pivotal
right right yeah 100% I mean the off
component is so important to everything
because like if you're a like a lot of
structures for instance uh we saw this a
lot in the car hacking where uh as an
example like you have Sirius XM at the
top where there's all these different
vehicle Brands beneath it like for you
know whatever but the Sirius XM Service
is like the authenticated one so each of
those car car companies has like an API
key that they use globally so it's like
once you if you can leak that key you
change the context between like one user
with access to one thing and then like
you leak the key and then you can talk
to that service access to that backend
service yeah exactly right so one
example there is like you know maybe
you're fuzzing for you know secondary
contact stuff and you throw in like a
new line character for a URI parameter
instead of like your account ID maybe
you do one two three% z d and then you
get a stack Trace back where it's like
the API call to internal. company.com
question mark API key equals and you're
like aha I see the API key you take that
and then you're like hey team this is
allowing me to access anybody's stuff so
you give them right but like you said
the authent the yeah it's this sounds
like a very
real maybe yeah maybe maybe it is but uh
you know doing some uh hacking on the
program recently I don't know if you can
disclose their bugs but there's a lot of
similar stuff like there right with the
with the secondary contact
stuff yeah like a yeah there's tons of
uh a lot of the for instance like a lot
of people hunt for actuators like really
heavily and like when you start
exploring like actuator secondary
contact stuff it's really fun because
it's like you know in some Javascript
file somewhere there's like this route
which is reverse proxy maybe it's like
API gw- you know internal slash or
something then you hit that route and
then that's where you pend your actuator
ends or like do do semicolon actuator
ends and then like it lets you kind of
hunt more thoroughly you're hit I guess
in this scenario you're hitting Dev API
API Dev end points using just this um
new secondary context sort of path
traversal so going through the front end
then traversing on the back end hitting
these actuator end points which wouldn't
be exposed publicly because of probably
path limitations um through the reverse
proxy and and then like are you normally
hunting for things where it's going to
dump the full response back to you
without any modification or are you you
going to try to hit these things blind
because a lot of times there's a parsing
of the response from that backend API
and then that that kind of Hecks up your
your visibility into the back end
right right yeah the having a response
is beautiful it makes you so happy when
you see that HP response leaked back to
you you feel amazing but a lot of times
it is blind right and I was with another
researcher Nathaniel it really is um
it's like a I would say too like to
finish that bit like a Nathaniel lner
donut um I was with him on a trip and I
like storm into his hotel room like
manically with my laptop I'm like if I
do ABC it doesn't do anything but if I
doxyz it does this thing but like I
can't reproduce it on this one and like
he he's looking at me I've sat there for
six hours trying to figure it out and
he's like this guy like what is he
talking about like it's absurd because
there are so many conditionals that
relate to like the uh you know like
you're trying to explain to friend
you're like if I do a pound sign does
this Behavior if I do an Amper standand
it's this behavior and like you have to
like really build out this like brain
map for each individual case right I
think the most complicated like
secondary context bug I had was like
this stored uh you would add a value to
a database with like an and sign and
like change the you change the format
from XML to Json yeah and then like on
another endpoint You' call it and it
would get retrieved it like and it was
just how you identify so it's like a
stor secondary cont I've never even
thought about a stored secondary
context yeah logically a lot of times uh
it can
be some things I think you can look for
there if it's like external services
like a external apis that you know for
instance uh you know are they leveraging
some third party API that has an API key
or like is there one you've already
identified that's like you can kind of
add on to um but they're so Case by case
right like one service has like one
behavior and you have you have to build
mind maps I guess yeah it it when you're
talking about the external Services it
makes me it reminds me of the Starbucks
bug and just to give a a quick overview
of this um like essentially what in this
scenario we actually had access to the
full response right that was coming back
and and we were able to on that one we
were able to path Traverse back on on
this Starbucks API and hit it was it was
a third party right it was Microsoft was
it
graph
yeah it was a Microsoft Graph Search I
think it was like a they had like a I
don't know if it was a third party
service or was a utility they had but it
was connected to their core their their
core Starbucks 100 million user Records
Was it was connected to and so
essentially like we were working on this
together and what amazed me when we were
working on this together was one that
that you identified one that leaked the
full response which allowed us to get so
much more interesting data back but um
uh but for two you were able to Brute
Force these paths along the way and I
just I don't know man I don't know maybe
it's just because I don't do a lot of
brute forcing as a part of my
methodology but it's just that's just
some and frons fron does it even weirder
I mean fron BR forces it as well but
fron also just has like this sick sense
of like you know what I bet customer is
before this and and it's like and then
he'll guess because we we were working
on this Target and it was like was we
weren't allowed to brw force they said
explicitly literally no BR Force please
do not brw force it okay and so we're
like we need to brw force it because how
are we going to figure out the paths you
know that we're traversing and Fran's
just guessed four paths
deep and I'm like that's so good you've
got to be kidding me man um so I guess
for this in your experience with the
brood forcing what is your approach to
that what wordless are you using are you
generating custom things you know is it
just something I've got to start doing
that I'm not doing
yeah I mean a really a really simple
list I like to use um it's in burp by
default but it's like server side
variable names and it's just like heard
you know path parameter yeah exil Mike
Robert showed me this like he uses it
from time to time for like parameters
and stuff but I think if you go to the
simple list it's like Ci variable names
but uh the thought process for trying to
Brute Force the past or guess the path
is like one it lets you confirm that
like you're not just traversing to like
the same request you're on because a lot
of the times what will happen is like
you think you're traversing but in
reality it's like a normal side like API
request where it's been condensed down
to the normal request so you're actually
just calling yourself so but yeah it's
very you're like oh I'm just you know
you like spam some about and you're like
delete messages you're like never mind
ignore me um but the uh but BR forcing a
pth is really fun because like you know
you can kind of guess like for instance
if it's bronze I've mispronounced his
name for 10 years you know so I
apologize um but he he would doing a
customer like makes a lot of sense where
you can kind of guess the format is like
V1 you know V2 V3 whatever but building
it out um I wish there was more General
tips but it really is Case by case basis
you know are they using camel case up
lower case upper are they separating are
you looking at the front end a like
paths for that to to determine that
information or you because I guess at
some point it's getting proxied back
through so maybe they're using similar
name conventions on the back end as
well yeah that's one thing that uh you
can kind of pick up on is like on the
front end if they refer to your account
as like accountor ID or something like
that you know those variable names that
are like normal you can kind of like
interplace those
um most of the time I'll just send it
through if there's no rate limiting I
have like a massive word list that chubs
gave me that is like 500,000
good they're really good yeah um so so I
did want to ask
um you mentioned that you have these
mind maps that you do um can you maybe
talk a little bit about what that means
to you and sort of like how that plays
into any note taking you do and like cuz
again like you typically are hacking on
very large scale targets and these are
ongoing engagements for weeks months at
a time
um and so there's a lot of information a
lot of data a lot of connecting parts
together and even on single like small
scope programs that exist and that can
be hard to track we've talked a lot
about note taking and all that kind of
stuff how do you keep track of
everything how how are you remembering
these Gad is it all just like a bulletin
board in your mind that is very just
like fragile or is or you are you
writing stuff down like can you talk a
little bit about that I wish I can
hardly remember what I had for breakfast
yesterday um mostly it's a Discord
Channel with people like mostly if I
find something interesting anything
interesting whatsoever I'll post like
the Javascript file I found it then if
it was a Javascript file and then like
the route and then maybe talk a little
bit about it because I'm normally trying
to communicate to somebody else in the
group chat like hey this is interesting
for this reason so I kind of like
catalog that and I can go back to it um
and then like Ping messages things like
that but for building out like you know
on like the longer engagements like
building out an understanding it's a lot
of like
uh you know maybe you go to developer.
company.com you register for an API key
and you kind of look through their API
requests so for instance uh we could
kind of transition this if you wanted to
but we found a vulnerability I think it
was on uh
versel um yep yeah but versell is a
really good example because for versel
versell has this API where they talk
about like all of their API requests
that you can make yourself as a
developer and there's a custom endpoint
on the versel website that takes in a
parameter of your account ID and it
basically generates a screenshot of your
website so it was like
slity there yeah yeah it was super fun
um but what was really interesting is
that when you give it the the parameter
for the website so it's like your SL
account ID website ID maybe like 123123
4 or
something you could actually um Traverse
the 12 34 and overwrite the full API
call and what what I realized is that
from reading the noral documentation for
verell it was actually making API
request to itself that was a normal
documented process that you could read
as a person right so we reproduced it
and we realized that what it was doing
is it was fetching a Json response from
a particular endpoint and it was parsing
out the URL parameter so this API
request to make a screenshot it would
pull this the URL from the website ID
and then it take a screenshot of that
specified URL how you sus that out how
did you know that it was pulling that
from the Json response you had to have
seen the response somehow right
so I never I never saw saw the response
but what I did is I figured out the
request by I did the thing that you know
fron said where you're backtracking
every single request until you rebuild
the full request and then uh in that
response I was like it has to be hitting
this specific endpoint and the only
thing from this response that makes
sense is the UR parameter what
so this is this is the kind of [__] I'm
talking about dude like how so so so you
Traverse back you look at the path and
then you just say Okay gu um there is
going to be in the the Json
response at the root level no like data
you know data call in this or whatever
there's going to be a URL attribute and
then they're going to read that and
that's the only thing they're reading
from the response are you kidding
me yeah it's a bit of like you know
there's you use the website enough a
little bit I don't know there's just
something like you slowly build it up I
think from like hacking on the same
Target for a while right and then like
can leverage that like and I think the I
think the final exploit for that was
like uh you could upload your own data
to versell and then you could backtrack
the API to load your own data and then
you would load your uploaded Json and it
would sign that URL and then you could
basically load anybody's staging domains
or bypass their SSO because what it was
doing was uh like you know signing URL
using your own token so like or signing
you the URL using a master token from
verell that had access to everybody's
stuff right um wow so so let me get this
straight this is this is nuts so what
you did is you find a secondary context
path reversal you identify by using
whatever the heck that was just a second
ago big brain nonsense that you need to
put a
URL Sam I I I really actually can't even
wrap my head around this so because
you're not even getting a hit you're not
even hitting an external server what
what you're guessing is that you went
all the way through this this whole
thing and then you uploaded a Json file
to the account and then traversed and
hit that and then you were deciding okay
I need to put a URL parameter in there
like a a URL Json value in there Sam
that's ridiculous that doesn't make any
freaking sense
Sam well it's a lot of uh I don't know
it's a lot of guessing is what it sounds
to me it's a lot of guessing intuition
which which is very for for me that is
definitely not my strong suit in
bounties like most of my stuff is very
much I think logically oriented in
logical flows but this was a lot of
guessing and a lot of intuition what I
mean is is it just something that you
feel when you're doing this because that
like and and I can I can understand that
in some scenarios like the fron thing um
with traversing back and then guessing
the path like that amazes me for sure
but I can understand it a little bit
because like okay you know you
understand the architecture of apis but
something like this where you're
guessing the structure of the response
and you don't even have it hitting your
own server so it's not but you have to
like upload a Json file and then
Traverse to that and
then help yeah yeah so so so I was I'd
like to say um you mentioned intuition
here and I was listening yesterday to a
really interesting podcast about
intuition and like when you can and
cannot trust your intuition okay and
intuition is one of those things that's
like really built up over time um as
like a skill where like you back to
chess right you see this all the time
with chess where chess Grand Masters um
they have played chess for so long that
they have a mental intuition of what
moves make the most sense even if they
can't really explain why it makes sense
because they've done it so many times
for so long they've thought about so
many different hands and scenarios and
and moves and everything that they're
like you know this makes the most sense
I can't really explain why but it does
and they're right um and I think a lot
of that is the same with bug Bounty
where it's like this intuition that you
hone in over time um both on individual
targets but also like as a whole right
so I think uh I was I was looking back
through our messages because uh like a
month ago you You' said this thing that
really stuck with me and you're like
there's a five-day hump on any program
quote fron Rosen on this and if you
brute for brute brute force past this
you become an Unstoppable force and I
love that because I think that is
like your intuition being like hang on a
second I'm I'm a dull right now you got
to sharpen me up a little bit and after
five days then you've got this specific
intuition for the Target you're looking
out right like when you're testing stuff
and you're like you know it's got to be
a URL parameter and in the response in
this Json body it's because you've got
five plus days of like banging your head
against the wall basically going back
and forth with like what is this
developer doing like what why why do
they make this Choice oh they do things
like that oh okay that's weird but all
right I guess that's just how they do
things and you just sort of build this
this like understanding of how a
specific company does things internally
um and back to the intuition part right
when you can trust your intuition is
when you're in an environment that is
like slow to change and so especially
when you've honed your intuition on a
Target that Target is not going to be
like yesterday we were doing things this
day this way but tomorrow we're going to
do it completely differently yeah right
and so you can actually hone your
intuition on a Target like really really
well because you do understand and how
they do things you can build up an
understanding like implicitly internally
of like okay this is probably how
they're actually doing this and I think
like that's something you do a really
good job of capitalizing on right I
totally agree with that like the uh that
happened too like Tesla this is sort of
don't hold on I'm not letting you weasel
your way out of that last one okay don't
even start with me right now okay so so
okay we're going to go to that one and I
want to hear that one but let's just you
know rewind a little bit here and and
finish this one up okay so you do some
big brain [__] and you figure out okay
there's a URL parameter what do you put
in the URL the URL parameter in the
parameter Json attribute in the response
uh of this traversed backend API request
are you putting in your own host are you
putting in uh initially
or yeah so originally what I did is I
put in my own host and I saw that
there's a like signed header which is
like a session it's like this is the URL
signed that way the server can like
access it you know because rell's God
key is being signed here and it loads
the god key
man I agree like I I was I was kind of
annoyed by it um and funny enough one of
the reasons that like we end up going so
deep on this bug is uh I think Ian Carol
knows how to like psychologically
manipulate me because uh whenever we
hack together he just tells me I was
sitting next to him at a hotel and uh we
were trying to hack on verel and he's
like there's no bug there like you can't
find I'm like I'm going to show you like
I will pull a bug out like if it's like
through a tiny little like fishing wire
starting to make S now Ian was Ian was
trolling you into this bug okay I
see he did this at
uh he did this at the uh recently yeah
but but yeah like there I tested my own
URL I saw it sending a request I saw it
was signed and then I was like well I
can't really sign anything arbitrarily
because I tried all the bypasses I did
like back slash you know at uh
credentials basically go you know to try
to get it to sign a URL that like try to
parse out uh part one of the URL where
it's like HPS victim.com or HPS uh sorry
victim.com
attacker.com where like it would sign
the URL for the victim website but give
me the signed credentials and then I
could take those credentials and
authenticate but what end up happening
that was a lot easier is we could just
pass in the victim URL directly so
there's no bypass needed because it
would just screenshot so what you were
trying to do there was somehow leak to
yourself the signed headers but
but you know the request has to be sent
to you so it it it isn't going to work
that way right because you can only sign
things that are going to be pointing
towards your own domain so then you just
put in the victim's website directly and
use the functionality on the
website exactly right because I was I
was annoyed I was like there has to be
some like differentiator between the HP
request actually firing and then like
the security parsing for the URL so I
was looking for any difference between
the two right because if the security
parsing was slightly different yeah
exactly um but yeah that was kind of the
process for that but then how did you no
no no no no no Sam but then then how did
you how did you know the I mean did you
just pass in was it just like hgps
victim.com
whatever exactly yeah yeah yeah it was
very simple for that part okay so you
don't you didn't have to like guess some
sort of path or anything like that with
the IDS for the victim it was literally
just you give them the victim website
and it just returns you an image of the
victim's
website exactly yeah and I was really
happy with that very simple so that part
was simple okay solid very cool man okay
so now talk about Tesla so yes intuition
you H your intuition and you said this
this happened on Tesla as well yeah sure
so for Tesla I was really frustrated
because like I really want I have I own
a Tesla and I like I really wanted to
hack it for a while and the Tesla API is
like really fascinating because like
there's like a single API for the Tesla
owners to use that can do all the stuff
for the Tesla cars and the authorization
a lot of times um one thing I noticed a
lot for like certain companies is
they'll do this thing while they'll
they'll sign a JWT or something and then
they'll have the value in the URL where
it's like maybe it's email email.com and
then in the URL they'll pass in like
email email.com and then to validate
that you're off they just compare the
two right for Tesla in particular I
noticed they had an account ID or a
vehicle ID and I was like in the JWT so
or jot however you want to say it don't
correct me podcast list but but uh
anyway the nobody's right on that one
stff but for Tesla is really cool
because there's this endpoint where you
pass in the vehicle ID and it was like
signing the JT but what you could
actually do is it was using a particular
integer parsing where if you appended
like ABC at the end of the integer it
would run parcent on it where it would
only retrieve the number so in the
actual logic check for authorization it
would pull out you know parse uh parse
ENT whatever you provided check if it's
you know valid that you're authorized to
access it and it would take the raw
value that you originally sent and it
would send it in a second request right
so what you could actually do that was
really neat is you could do like your ID
uh percent 2f do do percent 2f victim ID
and then it would basically it would
bypass the check via the parsent and
then it would take your raw request but
it would actually on the back end
Traverse to the victim account and you
get access the victim's vehicle wow dude
okay so I'm looking at this so the
reason that works is parse in in in
JavaScript if you pass it a string that
says 1 2 34 test it will return one two
three four one two three four yeah
exactly right that's hecked up that is
JS [__] if I've ever seen it um yeah but
that that's really helpful to know
especially on on node targets because
it's like they might be using parse in
to get the integer value for this thing
and then if they're using that so then
they they don't use the par value they
use the original value again in the
second backend API
request exactly and that's the fun part
because you can just provide in like the
victim ID it's really neat um and
there's a similar thing too with PHP
this is a kind of one something people
like I didn't know is that there's a
dollar signore request there's dollar
signore get dollar signore post and put
and whatever right but what's really
interesting is that if you do dollar un
sign request and you do a logic check
with dollar un sign request um like
let's say the ID parameter and then you
validate that parameter um you can
actually do if if if for any reason it
switches to get or post after that uh
requests could be like the one from the
get and then post could just the one
from the post uh what I'm trying to say
is that request is indifferent to or or
request is
like specific to one of those it's
either get or post and uh the logic
switches up once you switch to like
either get a post where you can
basically provide like question mark ID
equals 123 in the URL and then in the
post body you provide one 124 and
request pull is the top one and then
post is the second one ah and yeah
interesting it's to like a lot you've
seen that in the backend in the same
backend API call so like like where
you'll put the you the victim's ID or
let's say your ID in the URL and
then wait is this a part of the normal
functionality of this application where
they have the ID in two spots or are you
saying or is you specifically adding I
yeah specifically adding weird that's
super weird it was funny yeah it's
really funny because it was a for I was
playing like a Korean MMO which was like
super grindy and like you had to pay
like $100 if you wanted to like level
your character up or get a special item
or something and I ended up reporting
the bug so don't get mad at me yet um
but what you could do is it would have
like your package value so it's like a
$400 package and it pass that in and
then it would sign the whole request and
pass it off to the payment provider but
what you could do is like in the get
request you're like okay fine I'll pay
$500 and then the post request you do ah
let's actually change it to a penny and
that gives you the signed checkout URL
that's passed to like the payment
provider and you complete the checkout
process and you can only buy it for a
penny so then you get your $500 package
and I think I got a really funny email
from the game developer they said we
noticed some erratic activity in your
account you spent $3 million see this is
what I'm talking about like why do you
do this [__] like I understand the
hacking things that don't you don't have
like you know I I would love to know the
thought process say actually like when
you receive it evil like that are you
excited or you like oh [__] like uhoh
it's a little it's a little bit of both
um I hope they understand that like my
thing is like I like to like walk the
line between both it's like I hope
you're not GNA like P out like sue me
and get me in trouble and I hope that me
doing it isn't like too terrible for you
to deal with I I think it's similar to
like maybe if I did $100 or ,000 or
whatever but
like I don't know that that line is like
interesting to walk I think forgiveness
than permission yeah exactly
jail you know like I think like what
it's a very particular thing because
like you try I try my best not to like
actually I'm not like going out and
impacting the game economy I'm
immediately contacting them they report
it and like they're aware of my account
and stuff you know um but you still have
the coolest in the game for sure exactly
right like well it's funny too because
my buddy a long time ago when I was like
11 or 12 years old even I played video
games with this guy named buzzman and
buzzman did video game hacking and he
did tons of video game hacking and I
looked up to him a lot and he was like
this Belgian researcher and then uh when
I was 17 I checked his Facebook and he
runs like the one of the biggest game
security companies no way and uh he
actually had these people as a client
and I like passed it to him and he got
good PR he's like hello we found a bug
from you know and it this researcher
reported it um so really funny story
buzzman is a genius yeah very small guy
so okay so so just to bring that back to
the technical takeaway there which was
sometimes you can add parameters to the
see you and this is a very common idor
tactic as well you know where you'll see
a um you know an ID in the URL parameter
and in the post body and what it'll do
is the off check for the URL and then
not off check the the post body so that
that one's well established I you know
idor
mentality but this is this is also
applying in in this sort of scenario
where you can get you can add it
specifically to one or the other and I I
kind of right I I I kind of am curious
how that actually would work on the back
end because it's like okay you know I
can see how they would do path level
authorization in those other scenarios
but I can't really see how they'd be
like all right you know let's just say
it's PHP here um dollar signore get you
know that and then check but maybe it's
it's request but then it's overwriting
it you know but it you know what I'm
saying like how does this work yeah so I
think what originally happened was it
was a put request and it the off check
was using underscore request right and
when it was a put request I think PHP
was like oh cool it's a request it's a
put request it's coming from the body
right but then in the actual logic of
the application it did underscore get
right weird so off check request actual
functionality was get maybe there's like
if there's a get parameter that has this
specific spefic you know like user ID or
whatever then perform the off check and
then off check equals true or whatever
you know after that to wow very
interesting Sam I hadn't I had never
thought of that that's that's a that's a
pretty cool one to to take away um and
that's mostly regarding authorization
stuff for these or or I guess like you
said it could override values
application Level values as well and it
makes me think of a um client side PSAL
that I recently found which is my my
[__] right now I just love client side
PSAL vulnerabilities but essentially
what it was is um you know the the
target would send a an empty uh post
request to a given endpoint once I've
done the the client side patchers on the
URL um and I needed it to send
parameters in that that request um and
to to you know manipulate the
application Level logic add an admin
user to the organization and what I did
instead was just added them to the query
parameter with the path deveral so I
just did you know question mark yeah
user ID
you know and you know type equals admin
yeah and you see this a lot actually
where where Modern we Frameworks they've
made it significantly easier to use one
thing to reference parameters right
whether that's get or post or it's like
I just want I don't really care how it
comes in if it's post request or get
request I just want the parameter called
ID right it makes my web application
more flexible for but for an attacker
it's like okay well what if I provide
both like what is what is request.
parameters ID now I really I really like
like that that that's pretty
rad very very cool tip I'm trying to
look through here and see some of the
other things we have associated with
secondary uh context PSAL before we move
on to some of your research oriented
stuff um the or the other thing that I
see here is so we covered fuzzing for
endpoints um we've kind of mentioned
this on the on the Pod before but
figuring out where you are in that sort
of backend API is something you're
really good at and also actually I want
to come back cuz we didn't finish the
Starbucks the Starbucks thing one of the
other things that I realized was really
awesome about your Starbucks path
traversal was that the traversal was SL
or backslash do dot backs slash dot
backs slash right that was the traversal
SE sequence right where normally it's
just dot dot slash or you know dot dot
back slash but in this one you had to
space it out with dots in between why
were you doing that and what kind of
similar methodologies do you have with
that that may
help yeah that's time I think that was
an AI W byass which is really funny
because A's grown so much since then
yeah so if you did like do do slash it's
like stop that's too many backward
slashes but you're like do slash do
slash dot do slash and it's like all
right you know like that checks out and
I think maybe a even like in the blog
post it was like kind of a call out
because I was like yeah WS are bad this
is why this worked so I think maybe
they're like damn we got to fix not
saying AC my I'm the reason my fix her
thing but it was a little call out to AC
my like damn this was like kind of
embarrassing you guys need to get your
stuff together maybe pay better bounties
so so I mean when you're doing this I've
seen you do like even spaces and new
line character what kind of stuff are
you trying in order to achieve these
backend traversals and what kind of
stuff have you seen work with any
consistency yeah so one person who
really kind of helped and like kind of
get my methodology good this is Andre or
sorry Andre zerox ACB um Andre Baptista
I think is how you say last name but he
is uh one of the best like has one of
the best methodologies he made a tool
for this where it's like if you're
trying to Traverse directories there are
certain areas where you should be
fuzzing so for instance you could do dot
dot percent z00 to FF slash so then
instead of you would basically add
before the slash a character there and
then you enumerate through all the hex
code and then you know maybe percent z d
gets removed when it gets like
transacted to the next API and then
turns into this is recollapse is that
right yeah recollapse yeah uh recollapse
is great um so my methodology for like
trying to figure out if directory foral
works is like try the normal stuff you
know do dot backs slash do do percent ZD
SL do dot whatever but then if I can't
figure it out I'll just send it to
Intruder and then do z00 FF okay and
I've had like really yeah I've had some
good luck just like with random stuff
like percent 09 like a tab or something
sometimes for like net applications
would work and yeah really fun no I I
like that that whole Brute Force the the
URL or the URL decoding space
essentially um percent z z z to% FF that
that's that's quite good I and I use
that often as well um and you know
sometimes there's some weird Unicode
bypasses that that won't hit um but
those are pretty pretty rare edge cases
and I I kind of that's something that I
would like to put a little bit more
thought into is how can we
apply like I I mean there's too many
Unicode characters so we can just
bruteforce the whole Unicode space but
it would be really interesting to
categorize like okay these are like
white space is Unicode characters or
something like that that might get
converted and make those into a list for
birute forcing as well because that
would be really helpful to have in that
in that list as
well 100% and there was a good uh blog
post too I think it was like Unicode s's
for GitHub to bypass email OA flows I
could maybe Google it really quick it
was a
um GitHub unic code bug Bounty we'll
see find
it you said it was
GitHub Turkish yeah Turkish dotless eye
Turkish dotless
um
yeah oh wow this is the this
is this is one of my favorites Andre has
another thing for this I don't I'm not
going to give the exact EUR but it's
some somewhere on his website he has a
normalization table that I use all the
time and it's it's very similar to this
where it's just like you know all the
standard characters and then under every
single one it's just a list of all the
normalization possibilities like
different varieties and stuff of that
character and you can just go through
and you can try them you know on your on
your you know your Target and I use that
all the time when I'm trying to bypass
filters
I'll send you a link to it'll keep DM
you right now just
send send me Unicode
list that's great okay so so Sam just
why don't you talk us through this so
hacking github's oath with Unicode
Turkish doless ey how does this
work yeah so I think it was a email
issue where basically like GitHub
supported a bunch of different out flows
so I think that when you did uh scroll
through really quick
ah so they would put the Turkish doless
I after the G in GitHub at github.com
right oh yeah exactly and and then uh
yeah it emails the original one and
actually show this up as the second one
so you could just basically steal
people's so I I think what what happened
was like the email client or the
authorization was like oh that's you
know uh a different domain that's not
github.com but yeah there's an issue
there somewhere where it confused these
these Unicode normalization bugs are
every time I I see this I think of Andre
because of his just legendary bugs he's
pulled off at almost every live hacking
event he's been to he's done something
with crazy with these Unicode
normalization bugs um there there's a
lot of stuff I mean Andre is one of
those people I think that especially us
three have pulled a lot of we've done a
lot of hacking with him and we've pulled
a lot of inspiration off him as well
like even just like the leaking stuff
that we were talking about earlier like
that was Andre's first LG mph was
leaking a token through like an external
request to his server from like an
internal you know thing that was like a
master token like same you know very
very very very similar type stuff and
that was five plus years ago so here we
are full circle yeah that was crazy and
I yeah I have to call it out too because
like Andre is one of those people where
it's not just computers like when he's
hacking he's like this is the G Galaxy
like this is the Matrix like we're in
space right now like going through like
portals and like it's so much larger
than just like an API for him it's like
yeah it's I love the energy is so good
love Andre so much I love Andre's energy
yeah yeah so actually on the topic of
energy and we'll Circle we can we can
Circle back to technical stuff but this
was something on the philosophy thing
that I did want to want to highlight
with you um you have this
really intense energy um in a good way
like when when it comes to hacking like
when you are focused on a Target Justin
always describes me as like a laser beam
that he can uh he can nerd snipe to
point in the right direction and I I I
view Sam as like uh the Death Star Ray
in that same sense right so like it's
like 100x where when you're really
fixated on something when you're focused
on like I want to get this thing like
there is nothing that's going to really
stop you from doing that um and you have
like this like Industrial sized fan on
your flame right so how do you like how
are you able to like do you does it just
come naturally all the time like you
just find yourself in these situations
or do you find um that you fall out of
that head space and that you have to do
certain things to get yourself back in
there yeah I don't know I think honestly
a lot of it stems from like uh hacking
was like one of the original things
where it's like I felt like a this is
gonna sound so like kolude psychologist
whatever but like the uh original like
a sense of uh I don't know appreciation
was like finding something cool so like
I have this really deep down thing where
it's like if I want to like prove a
point and like find a bug that's how I
feel like a sense of validation for my
fears and stuff or whatever so like if I
if I have a goal which I feel like is
like interesting to me and like I prove
a point to somebody or something like
that you know like it's like I wanna I'm
GNA do it so like it Transitions and it
comes up pretty naturally where like I'm
like yo like that thing looks
interesting and I bet I could do it um
and it's like a fun I don't know how to
describe it but it it comes very
naturally where it's like you know for
instance like yes something just get
like gets under your skin a little bit
like Ian being like there's nothing here
or like whatever it is or or you just
being like that's really interesting I
wonder if that's possible or whatever it
is exactly just sort of like following
that that that dopamine or whatever that
that interest yes examp a perfect
example of that like recently too is
like uh is it okay if I transition to
the hacking a little bit okay yeah
absolutely so uh yeah like I I had a
call on my ISP technician because like I
moved into a new house and like I
couldn't get it set up and like it was
just kind of frustrating they're like
I'm gonna remotely change your password
I'm like you can do that like you can
remotely change my modot's passord I was
like I had no idea that was possible and
I was like I wonder what they have
access to to do that because oh my gosh
I have a yeah it it was fascinating
because I'm like this is really cool so
like I spent a while investigating my
own ISP and I eventually found this
vulnerability because because like deep
down at the core of the ISP they had
built this internal API called sale and
what sale was used for was customer
support agents and normal people to
manage their router to push commands to
update their router view router settings
and it's called sale and it would
basically bypass the authorization later
to do things like update DMS or fetch
device pass or do things like that and I
like not just reset to fetch it as well
you you can do everything I mean you can
do this is the modem right this is this
is a modem and this is the modem they
issue to everybody it's not just their
their ISP modem it it's any compatible
it's it's fascinating right because to
even go back two years ago um to give a
little even more context is like I was
hacked like I I got hacked I was on my
laptop and I curled a box and what I
realized was that a third-party digital
otion IP was resending my exact same ISP
request so I thought originally my
computer was owned and then I opened the
URL on my iPhone and I saw the exact
same digital ocean IP was resetting that
same traffic so somebody somewhere was
like intercepting my traffic and I
researched it and it was an IP that was
related to like a fishing campaign and
uh basically what I think happened was
someone had compromised my modem right
and uh so sorry for so much background
for this but um it got me really
interested in like hacking IPS but
anyway I found found a way to remotely
uh you can remotely take over anybody's
router um you could update their DNS
update their password settings things
like that um via just their serial
number how you find how did you find
their that that API in the first
place yeah so what it was was uh there's
a it's the ISP that was affected um
there's a business management website so
for business customers and they have
access to like a little bit more
functionality so if you're a business
customer and you want to manage your uh
router motem um to like update stuff
remotely or see the connected devices
remotely it would take in your request
and like pass it down and what I
realized is that there is a bypass to
Traverse down and access to Swagger
files AP sorry I'm gonna pause you and
back up a little bit there why do you
why did you why were you looking at the
business I mean do you have access to
that business panel yourself or or were
you just looking at this as like oh this
looks like something related
yeah that's that's what I was doing
originally well what I originally
assumed is that there isn't any
segmentation
between and I thought that at the
protocol level from a support level it's
using the same like sale protocol I
assumed it was based on a research
protocol beforehand or no I'm just
trying to get into the yeah space a
little bit
here I think at the time I didn't know
about that it was specifically called
sale but I realized that there's a tool
set internally and there was like a
little documentation that was like
scattered across like GitHub or whatever
where it had like reset device whatever
but uh to clarify
like I knew it was possible and then I I
kind of thought about it and there's the
customer facing website which is very
restricted lockedown and then there's
like the Business website which has you
know if
you're like a business you can manage
more stuff you have multiple devices
it's like an easier interface right so
that was the thought process but
I dug at the Business website and uh I
eventually found an API which let you do
those sale commands and I found the
second vulnerability where there was a
leaked secret which was used to encrypt
the router serial number in the pipe in
the flow um so I could basically decrypt
and encrypt any router serial number
that was passed in that protocol to do
like anything so is this an UNO API or
were you offed into the Business
website full it was uh fully unoff yeah
it was unoff everything was found it in
the JS files or were you brute forcing
it it was in yeah JavaScript it was
basically the flow was website to
JavaScript to directory traversal
Swagger files to API call uh from a
traversal so it's like a secondary
context thing where you Traverse to
another internal routing thing and then
uh in the JavaScript it has the encrypt
functionality because I saw the router
value and I was like that's like not a
normal string it's not so I realized
it's encrypted so you could decrypt it
it and then uh through that you could
it's absurd to think about to me because
it's if you're the FBI you have an
office building that uses this ISP for
your internet right and if someone was
to like man in the middle of your
network they have to like go in your
network and do the whatever but like you
can just update DNS via this via the
serial number and it's like innumerable
and it's just we could also search by
customers by name or business name so
it's like you could Target like it's
just wow dude that's crazy so go ahead
sorry well and this is on your ISP who's
like you know one of the largest I mean
they also have Monopoly where I live um
they're like one of two isps in my area
I think most people use them and um you
know they're they're a huge huge massive
megga
Corp did did they even have a security
contact like I I'm almost certain they
don't have a bug b program right no they
had like a they maybe had a security
page like a responsive dis they did have
a responsible disclosure page but you
had to like go through a couple people
to actually get to somebody um yeah they
didn't really seem to have like a super
sophistic I couldn't find a security
contact um they maybe had a ceso but
they weren't reachable they didn't have
an email or LinkedIn that accepted the
invite or anything like that um wow yeah
no way to contact it so let me just I'm
gonna try to concisely do this because
this is really something special like
what the way that you have found this
whole path um and it's something a
little bit more foreign to me because
for me a lot of what hacking looks like
is get the main application figure out
all of the
functionality figure out all of the
logic you know find all the requests
start correlating information Deep dive
the stack you know that sort of thing
but this whole thinking about it from an
architectural level is very different so
you had a call with a support agent the
support agent said the wrong thing to Mr
Sam Curry and said I'm G to reset your s
here's like mental note very interesting
oh thanks okay bye [__] immediately
start fire and you're thinking okay so
they have some way to remotely reset my
my router I bet that it's easier to
access that through the business portal
than it is through the customer portal
maybe you went to the customer portal
first or whatever and then but then you
decided to go to the business portal go
to the business portal no off no nothing
that doesn't scare you off you're just
looking at the JS files you find unof
API access that that you can have you
pass RS it hit the Swagger then using
the Swagger you find I mean I imagine
the Swagger did have documentation in it
for all the yeah okay so at that point
you're like all right I'm good to go
then from the Swagger file
you're are you hitting is it a reverse
proxy or is it a secondary context thing
on that API or was it a secondary
context thing before that to hit the
Swagger
file it was a secondary context to hit
the sper file and that opened the door
everything was connected at that point
in the secondary then now you've got the
keys to the kingdom with the Swagger
file and the UN API and you can just
encrypt and decrypt IDs because of that
secret and then you can take over
any any freaking router in your whole
ISP yeah yeah it's it's crazy to think
about because it's like and and shout
out to Z for helping me with the
JavaScript too because the encrypt
function was at a certain point had a
break point in the JavaScript to
actually call that JavaScript um Z's the
master at this he's done like a lot of
really cool research
if you're setting an encrypt or if
you're setting a breakpoint then that JS
would have to be triggering which I
imagine would only happen after off
right so did he have to like somehow
hijack that flow and Trigger that
function
or so there was a submit registration
end point that you could hit and it
would encrypt your pen code so you
didn't actually get approved or anything
but you could encrypt your uh like you
know one two three four it send in
crypto
value that's awesome this is such cool a
cool little like pocket of research too
cuz I've thought a lot about this like
modems are such a weird spot a lot of
modems especially like the provided ones
they don't give you any way to interface
with them right like my modem for
example has like a fiber line going into
it it's an ENT I guess but and then it
just outputs ethernet to my you know my
my network right but how do I talk to
the the box that like gets fiber right
like that is Con that's talking to the
ISP that does some theoretically some
negotiation or communication back with
the ISP so that some random person can't
just plug a fiber in and get internet
for free right right like I you know
it's like how how does all that work
it's such a such a weird like yeah I I I
love just like peering into that I think
there's a lot more interesting research
you could do there the on boxes too are
super pro like proprietary like I had
the the guy was at my house I was like
can I buy one of those he's like nope
they got to come from the ISP and you go
to the on website yeah yeah you can't
buy them yourself like you can maybe get
them off eBay but yeah very proprietary
that would be such a fun live hacking
event if some like you know Verizon or
Cox or whatever is just like all right
here's your house and they give us a
little like you know router hack you
know that would be so be awesome um i'
love it all right dude so that was a
that was a great a great vul story thank
you for getting into the technical
details with that that really helps me
understand from a bigger perspective
what your methodology is for finding
these sort of Fringe assets and going
after these goals that you got um the
next one that I kind of want to talk
about is your next nextjs research um
that you did 2022 I think uh and and I
if I understand correctly this was a was
something that came from the fact that a
lot of companies are using this
framework now specifically in the crypto
space and that motivated you to look
into it
right right exactly like one big thing
for me was like uh with crypto it's
always been kind of crazy to me because
like the huge thing for crypto is
integrity right if you look at the CIA
Triad confidentiality is like the only
thing you need to really worry about is
like leaking your keys uh being like
availability it's like if it goes down
it's like whatever you still have the
chain access it's like a static website
who cares right but the Integrity is
like super important right so like if
I'm a normal person and I want to go to
Unis swap to like trade a million
dollars for this for a million dollars
of that I trust unis.org and I'm not
really going to do too much additional
verification like you know nobody's
doing like hash verifications of the
JavaScript or whatever they're are it's
all very like metamask swap I trust the
domain name right so the idea for me is
like if you can get xss on nextjs which
is what all the crypto websites use then
you have this like huge huge Integrity
issue where it's like you know there's
non-stop fishing domains and this was
the the first case that i' personally
seen someone leverage subdomain takeover
for a fishing domain because I saw on
Twitter someone had taken over like
something. ferrari.com and then hosted
like an nft giveaway or something right
and it's like yeah it was really cool to
see I'm like hey sub take over like
someone's actually exploiting that for
like purpose right that's not good yeah
exactly and the one actual instance of
it being exploited in the wild exactly
like so that that was always fascinating
to me so like the nextjs like every
single website you proxy it you see unor
next and you're like oh my God same
thing over and over and over so for me
it's like let's investigate this and
maybe there's like a core issue because
personally like versel and netfi and all
these companies they're like great
they're great companies but like the
bloat um associated with it there's a
really funny quote actually from like
Whitey cracker on a Blog he wrote a long
time ago and he says uh if any one of
these like all it takes is like
one of these like fren JavaScript
framework developers to die of like
Aderall overdose and like a quarter of
the internet goes down nobody can ever
fix it again because like it's such a
particular Library so like the XZ thing
that that's happening right now like
live XZ we came like so close just like
Graz the sun with uh with how that could
have been and it's the same thing right
it's like otics is one really widely
used library or framework or something
to get popped in a fundamental way and
everybody's like
everyone's [__] that that affects
everything yeah yeah exactly and for for
nextjs especially too it's like at the
time I was so focused on crypto I was
like let's try to Target all the crypto
websites so I work with shs on this one
and we went deep on the source code for
the actual like image proxy
functionality basically what they've
done is they've baked in this like image
optimization feature where you know
maybe in the past You' had like an
external image that has to load each
time but like instead of reaching out to
the other website it does the closer
server and it optimizes it and caches it
so you don't have to like waste the
network traffic
so what that actually does is like the
server itself is originally making that
request to fetch the image right so if
you loaded like uh I think it was uncore
ipx SL external URL it would uh oror IX
trusted URL like percent 2f image.png
what you could actually do through
investigating the source code is you
could add a header to overwrite the
external URL that it reaches out to and
then it would cach it and we what we
realized is that you could do yeah SPG
files and by doing an external SPG file
and caching it on that URL you could
save like percent 2f test.html or test.
SBG and then it would cash the xss
payload you could send it to somebody
else and since it was at like a library
level you could do it like on any
website right and so did you get that
from reading the source code for for
that I imagine that wasn't just
experimentation no yeah it was a it was
a bit of both um mostly it was source
code because like you could trace
everything is public which is kind of
it's one of like those like Silicon
Valley like open source but sort of we
like give you a trial or something so
yeah I actually want to ask about this
because I I think I'm being a little I
don't fully understand the whole
infrastructure for this so obviously we
see a lot of nextjs stuff on the on the
client side um but is this is this you
know I'm having a little bit of trouble
correlating this to to what it is I mean
obviously they've got some server side
functionality we see a bunch of stuff
with that on the client side is it like
a full stack solution for that
or yeah so nexts is uh it's a full stack
solution or and it's kind of like a
framework it's essentially what it is is
a JavaScript framework and it does both
front end and back end so and what's
it's it's offered by I think for sell
versel is the originally they're the
original Builders maybe of of nexs and
versel is like here's xvs and if you
really want an easy way to deploy it
just come to our website right so a lot
of nexs that you see is actually
deployed through vel's website through a
sort of like AWS setup right this is a
full so and this is very interesting so
there's there's certain trade-offs
between the the server side and the and
the client side that are baked right
into it just like this image
optimization thing I see why that this
this sort of put off the arms in your
head because I hadn't really looked at
this structure before but what I had
seen is like um it does make me think a
little bit of this this Cloud flare
stuff that I that we talked about on the
Pod maybe last week or a couple weeks
ago um of like these SL CDN CGI endpoint
that's on literally every single website
um there's got to be some weird stuff
there man I swear uh right yeah any I
mean there's a lot of things that are
like this right like imagine if somebody
finds an xss Google tag manager oh my
God like yeah right it's like every
website in the world it's you know yeah
I think I was hacking on like that was
one of those things where it's like I
was hacking on like some really hardened
Target and it it was used by everybody
it was like something similar to like
venmo or something like that right and
what I saw was that there was a
JavaScript pency and the source and i'
never seen that domain before and it was
like a tenant based Javascript file so
like you could customize your JavaScript
for your tenant on that third party SAS
product and it was being added to this
so if somebody compromised that you've
now added the single point of failure
it's crazy yeah it's so interesting the
especially on these bigger hardend
programs this is something that I've
I've talked a little bit um about post a
live hacking event that happened in the
past year um with with some of the guys
afterwards it was just kind of
discussing like when you've got these
big targets that pay for impact that are
very very secure and locked down many
times the weakest link is going to be
these third party end points that they
that they or these third party providers
that they pull in without doing too much
of a security assessment on it because
you know they they may have very solid
security controls from uh from just like
you were talking about um before the
episode with with donut you know and
trying to build a an authorization
framework that just makes it impossible
at compile time to do an authorization
issue um you know they may have
protocols like that in place at their
organization but when the freaking
marketing team says I need this you know
Plugin or whatever for my my front end
they're not going to audit that whole
source code base you know um and yeah
and they can't continuously audit it
either right maybe they audit it once
and then in a year or two you know they
never get to see what happens and the
vul gets accidentally snuck in there or
committed by accident and yeah you know
such a risk it's a huge risk and then
and then you know like you guys were
saying as well all of the whole internet
is built on these like maintain your
building building
blocks it's it's depressing to see to be
honest and it makes you wonder ah isn't
open source awesome there needs to be
like some massive government grant or
something like that for open source you
know maintainers that are just like
please continue doing the thing you're
doing so that we don't lose our whole
internet
infrastructure that that would be
big um so yeah I think it makes a lot of
sense why you would Target nextjs and
that that um that Target or that ipx
piece of of how you're able to to cat
that pretty rad the other vulnerability
that I was looking at in here that
seemed pretty interesting to me was the
open redirect viore
neximage and just to be clear for
anybody listening to these these
vulnerabilities are long long patched
you know if they're running I don't know
something super old and it's not hosted
then maybe you'll still find these but
um these are long patched so it's mostly
just useful for the methodology um and
having H man having an open redirect on
any website that has underscore next you
know would be so clutch because it's so
helpful to have these and um when you're
looking for open redirects I see the
payload here was slashback slash
slashback slash slash right so there's
slashes in between and essentially
what's happening here or backslashes in
between is it's getting normalized to a
slash slash redirect right a SL payload
and that's why it's redirecting correct
do you have any other cool tricks like
that you for when you're doing open
redirect
searching um there's so many and they're
so dependent on the actual like
implementation uh honestly sitting there
and like my tips and tricks like I don't
know this is this is right Sam this is
why podcasting is tricky right because I
I said what I said earlier about
intuition you know and I said I'm not a
bunch of intuitive Hunter but that's
more more so from a from a top level you
know architecture perspective when
you're trying to explain why on a
podcast why you test the things you test
or what is your methodology it's so hard
when you don't have your hands on
something like if you were just if you
had your if I handed you a you know
closed
redirect and I said Sam make this an
open redirect uh you know I'm sure you
would be able to talk through the
concepts of what you're doing as you're
fiddling with it but when I say Sam
what's your methodology for open redr
it's real tricky
right right yeah exactly it's kind of
funny like trying to come up with like
condense like the knowledge into like a
you know a sense or whatever so be a
podcast thing that's like informative um
I totally agree like searching for this
in particular was fun because like the
goal for me was like well it essentially
was allowing local images like
explicitly so like for instance if you
wanted to proxy unor IMG question mark
image equals SL image.
totally fine loves it says well we're
going to try to find an image and if we
can we're going to proxy it for you and
serve it right and for me that's kind of
interesting because it's like well I
know that slash slash will route to an
internal like a uh external demain and
like a fully domain
name yeah so I was trying to play with
that for a while then what I realized is
that I was like well it doesn't like uh
two slashes in a row so like could do
like forward slashback slash and then to
make it finished you could do forward
SLB slash again and then you've got the
fqdn right and then uh what I realized
after that too was that I think if you
ended the URL in a path that was not
completed or if I look back through it
really quick
um yeah if you if you ended it in a
slash so next has his behavior which is
really funny the reason this
vulnerability exists is because uh in
xvs if you hit
and a full if if you hit a path and the
path doesn't exist that ends in a slash
for instance if you hit slash test slash
and that's not a real thing what it
tries to do is take you back to slash
test to see if it's a real thing without
the
slash yeah so what's cool about that
though is that at the time of reporting
it the theore
NEX IMG would actually send the as
request to itself and then you could
abuse that functionality because it
would return the redirect to the user
so then basically you would get uh open
redirect for any site because it would
try to send that request to itself and
then it would serve the response that it
got from itself which had
theback attacker.com wow so it was it
was creating you were sort of creating a
loop of sorts
there exactly very cool dude yeah it's
it It's tricky to explain all of those
different uh open redirect pieces but
one thing that's consistent with that is
like you have to have a very solid
understanding of browser redirect
mechanics and URLs and how URLs are
parsed in order to find all these and
then you just got to try to figure out
the places where oh the developer didn't
consider the you know double slash uh
being a a top level you know redirect um
versus an a um a relative so an absolute
redirect versus a relative redirect um
and so yeah no I really I really like
this one and man I wish this still
existed because what a gadget what a
gadget that would be man on so many
websites yeah and that's
inter well I was going to ask like did
you approach it at all from like the
static anal or like the just because you
have like the JS right in front of you
so it's but it was it just easier to
test it sort of blackbox than it was to
dig through a bunch of JavaScript code
and figure out how that works yeah
luckily for me I'm I'm a very nonsource
codee person I'll do fine with source
code and I enjoy it and I appreciate it
but for me uh I like to just test the
actual functionality versus trying to
dig into the code because one thing that
my philosophy a little bit is when the
developers wrote that code they wrote
what they intended and wanted it to do
and even though if you know the tricks
around it sometimes you'll trick
yourself and thinking that something's
working intended and if you take the
approach of like an external person
who's like well I don't think it's
working as intended we'll try to figure
it out then sometimes you can get better
results but it's cool to work with chubs
because shub
is a fantastic like source code auditor
so we kind of merged a little bit where
I was like smashing the keyboard and
he's like analyzing stuff in the source
and you can you can you bounce off of
each other too where you say hey I'm
seeing something weird at Dynamic
analysis go figure out why that's
happening and then you know they go
figure out why that's happening and it
leads you to a clear picture of like
okay that's why that's happening and you
can exploit it further because you now
have introspection into the code
surrounding The Fringe weird
functionality I like that I like that
all right man we are two hours and 20
minutes in right now so um let's go
ahead and and wrap up the last thing
that I I wanted to talk about here was
you mentioned before that you have um a
lot of success with Dev versus prod um
in the context of JWT is being used as a
form of of um of authentication you can
talk a little bit about that and maybe I
don't know if you have a story about it
but you can feel free to share a story
if you
do yeah sure so uh the dev versus prod
thing is really fun because uh if you're
a developer and you're writing like a
nextjs application and you have like you
know if I'm a startup and I start a
company and I use nextjs and I do all
the things correctly but let's say I
accidentally reuse the same key and I
store it in my source code and then I
deploy a Dev site and a prod site and
I'm provisioning user IDs for each
registered user if I register in Dev
I'll be user ID 3 or whatever but in
prod I'm like user ID 463 but a lot of
times what I could do is just copy over
the dev JWT to prod and then I could
access account number three and then
like some funny stories too with that um
it's just kind of part of my attack
methodology now for like nextjs websites
because it's just one of the things I
saw like a few
times yeah I think specifically for
nextjs because uh honestly with nextjs
it's getting a lot harder to test for
bugs I feel like because like you've got
everything in the JavaScript and like I
don't know it it's all all there but
like it just gets boring it's the same
thing over and over again so it's just
not like entertaining to hack on so I
kind of I've been trying to do this for
next websites because I know it's a
common thing I've seen um but yeah
copying the staging JT to prod and then
seeing if there's a indifference for
which account you get if the secret find
that there's normally one piece of
information they're basing their off off
of there like like an ID versus like an
email or anything like
that yeah a lot of times a lot of times
it's ID but other times it's email the
ID ones are sometimes harder to exploit
because it's like U ID based and then
you can't really do anything unless you
can control it but the ones that are fun
are the email ones that don't like
require confirmation um because say you
register like admin atomy.com and like
you do on one and the other and the
other one's not registered then yeah you
generate it just tet whatever account
you want and then just opt into
it exactly yeah and it's yeah it's been
vau for a long time or like kind of a v
class but I've seen it kind of pop back
up a tiny bit I think BBY Herby also
mentioned that this is a part of His
function or normal methodology for this
sort of thing and I know he's popped
some cool bugs with that in the past um
so there's definitely there's definitely
bugs to be found in that in that uh area
and I'm I'm kind of wondering as well
what your what your recon looks like
then because you do have this whole
thing where you're
like where you're going deep for sure
but you're also finding The Fringe
assets you need to find to get the
impact so to what degree do you spend
time on on recon versus focusing on
hacking applications you've
discovered yeah so Recon like I love
Recon for getting an understanding and
feel of the app friending finding like
you know dev. company.com versus prod or
and like kind of understanding their
infrastructure um I'm not a really big
Fringe asset Hunter so I'm not really
somebody who goes at like you know some
crazy subdomain that popped up for four
seconds onert Dosh right like I can't do
that it's not my style um but what I'll
do is I'll use Recon data to kind of get
an understanding like whether or not
there's aomi host for everything and one
of them is a non-ac my host and they can
change the host header and do you know
like that's how you gain info but um
what I'll do for targeting assets is
like try to pull together an
understanding like maybe there's a
domain that has like a Swagger file
maybe there's domain that has this and
then I'll try to use it to attack
whatever has the most functionality
whether that's dubdub duub my account
dot app dot mostly those core ones I try
to stick to dude that's one of the most
balanced approaches I've I've heard of
it takes on the Pod is like use Recon
data to the extent that it gives you a
picture of the organization and to
explain the full architecture of the
organization and then from there you
attack the thing that has the most
features in the most attractive features
as
well very right yeah I love that because
it's yeah there's another yeah there's a
hacker uh Cash Money Tanner he uh he has
a similar attacking style like jack
cable maybe even Herby but they're all
like swear to the fact they're like
manual hackers who they'll employ stuff
like they'll script stuff definitely
like I've seen Tanner script like crazy
stuff and he's done really well but like
mostly they seem like they manual
testers where it's like it's like why
wouldn't you go after the part of the
app with the most functionality like if
I could some random it's going to have
two API calls that are like engagers and
not versus the main app is like six
years of like 400 developers rotating in
and out of being fired new ones and like
you know what I mean 100% dude wow
that's that's a great way to wrap off
this PO is is that that really balanced
approach to Recon and in looking at an
organization holistically rather than a
individual web app um that's that's
definitely something for me to chew on
Joel did you have anything else you
wanted to toss out there before we boun
um no I mean I'll I'll open it up to Sam
because um you know I know we've talked
about a bunch of different things but
you know obviously hack compute and some
of the other stuff you're working on
your blog um you whereing people find
you and uh and and watch out for more of
your awesome research yeah uh I think
Sam curry. net and then uh haute.com
uh yeah I'm trying to continue to
publish like cool web stuff to Sam net
but I haven't done too I've been doing a
lot more so I'm kind of happy to be able
to publish some more stuff but uh
besides that like haute.com I want to
publish more UPC stuff um yeah mostly
thank you to Justin and Joel for putting
this together like I don't know if to
The Listener like behind the scenes is
so much effort like there's a full
Google doc of like 10 hours of like
writing out like and then researching
and figuring stuff out yeah so it's tot
honor um really really appreciate them
well thanks thanks for coming on Sam
we'd love to have you on and definitely
have you back on in the future to share
some of this cool research that's coming
off at uh at Sim curry. net so all right
that's the Pod cheers peace peace
[Music]
peace